[
  {
    "id": "1",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum engine oil temperature?",
    "answer": "129.5 deg",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4447931163012981",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "2",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the continuous oil temperature range?",
    "answer": "10 deg to 129.5 deg",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2202440504916012",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "3",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the engine oil temperature caution range?",
    "answer": "-45 to +10",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8395889089442788",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "4",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the minimum oil temperature for start (2mins)?",
    "answer": "-35 deg",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4983265078626572",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "5",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the minimum eng oil temperature?",
    "answer": "10 deg",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5608167038299143",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "6",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the engine pressure range for start (2mins)?",
    "answer": "0 - 13.8 Bar",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8912558984011412",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "7",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the minimum engine oil pressure?",
    "answer": "2.1 Bar",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0252305162139236",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "8",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the continuous engine oil pressure?",
    "answer": "4 - 8.5 bar",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8451961888931692",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "9",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the engine oil caution pressure range?",
    "answer": "2.1 - 4 bar",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2811835026368499",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "10",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum engine oil pressure (Trans max 10 min)?",
    "answer": "13.8 Bar",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7166012367233634",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "11",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What happens if both ENG MAIN switches are moved from OFF to IDLE at the same time?",
    "answer": "One engine will start first. When the start cycle is complete, the other engine will start. (06-88)",
    "ref": "06-88",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0125034139491617",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "12",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How many oil pumps are located within the MRGB?",
    "answer": "2",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "(01-16)",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4101072647608816",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "13",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In the event of a HYD PRESS failure on the No 1 system, what other indications may appear?",
    "answer": "P/R SAS would fail. (Card 36)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7554883882403373",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "14",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Engine start should be aborted if light-up is not achieved within what time frame?",
    "answer": "15 seconds. (Card 26 – No ignition by 20% N1 or 15 secs)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9613823159597814",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "15",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The transmission has demonstrated operation without oil for:",
    "answer": "25 minutes. (The ‘facts and figures’ notes page)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3770687161013484",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "16",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What colour is used on the CAD to display advisories?",
    "answer": "Green.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6727983644232154",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "17",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In normal flight, where do the FADECs draw their electrical power from?",
    "answer": "Directly from their respective alternator (PMA). (06-82)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0698409634642302",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "18",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Selecting the HYD TEST switch to position 1 results in:",
    "answer": "Simulating a leak in the No 2 HYD system, yaw pedal forces increase. (04-56)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3641606136225164",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical"
  },
  {
    "id": "20",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Does the MRGB bay have fire systems?",
    "answer": "It has no fire systems.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0768865002319216",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "21",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In addition to the Nr gauge, what are the indications when Nr ≥ 106%?",
    "answer": "Flashing CWP caption and audio gong. (3-10 of Flight Manual)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.757388174533844",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "22",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What indications are displayed on the triple gauge?",
    "answer": "Main rotor RPM and power turbine speeds for both engines.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5387546611018479",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "23",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The rotor blades of the Fenestron are unevenly spaced for what reason?",
    "answer": "To reduce tail rotor noise. (03-26)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0686695193871855",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "24",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the main rotor RPM adjusted in flight?",
    "answer": "Automatically by the FADECS on each engine. (06-80)",
    "ref": "06-80",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9942209436558188",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "25",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the correct actions following a GEN OVHT caution in flight? (Gen Temp > 205deg)",
    "answer": "Switch off affected GEN. If caption remains after one minute, shutdown affected engine and land as soon as practicable.",
    "ref": "Card 17 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9400702752172948",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "26",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How are the contents of the supply tanks separated (or not)?",
    "answer": "They are completely separate at their base. (06- 6)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4961639768444001",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "27",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the MRGB connected to the aircraft?",
    "answer": "4 ARIS dampers, 2 torque struts, 1 side load strut. (01-42)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6580152809619904",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "28",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "With a total fuel load of 120 kgs, how is fuel transferred from the main to the supply tanks?",
    "answer": "By two transfer pumps.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2515941588208079",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "29",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum engine oil temperature in flight (answer to the variant you have trained)?",
    "answer": "T2+: 110°C \u000b\u000bP2+: 129.5°C",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3543792800046503",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "30",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is fuel shut off to an engine initiated in the event of an engine fire?",
    "answer": "Automatically when the FIRE button is pressed. (7 – 8 Flight Manual)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1259429156780243",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire,fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "31",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What would happen to the FADECs if there was a double generator failure in flight?",
    "answer": "Nothing. (06-82)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.299656271468848",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "32",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Why are flexible couplings installed in the aft tail rotor drive shaft?",
    "answer": "To correct for misalignment and variations in length. (03-16)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1131757642142474",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "33",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the indications of a failure of a main fuel tank sensor?",
    "answer": "F QTY DEGR caution on the CAD.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.15403185877949",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "34",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "If both MRGB oil pressure switches detect low system pressure in flight, what warnings would you expect to see?",
    "answer": "XMSN OIL P cautions on the CAD, XMSN OIL P warning on the CWP, gong audio warning. (Flt Man 3-10)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6329895392991601",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "35",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When is the CAD/VEMD self-test sequence initiated?",
    "answer": "When the battery master switch is switched on.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1957674818113446",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "36",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In the cyclic control run, what is the purpose of the input isolating linkage?",
    "answer": "To eliminate undesired control inputs from the main transmission due to vibration.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7140484321862459",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "37",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Why must the MASTER CAUTION be acknowledged by pressing the CDS/AUDIO RESET on the cyclic?",
    "answer": "To permit other cautions to be displayed, if necessary. \u000b? TBC\u000bPossibly it's to allow the Amber Master Caution to reset and thus allow subsequent cautions to create a visual alert.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7563716364093125",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "38",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "If a parameter is invalid on the FLI, how is it displayed?",
    "answer": "The numerical value disappears and the title (e.g. TQ) is displayed is yellow.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4760103863663971",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "39",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "With both engines operating, what is the maximum continuous FLI limitation?",
    "answer": "FLI 9.0.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2664073826745152",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "40",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the maximum continuous AEO torque?",
    "answer": "2 x 69%.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2161979265511036",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "41",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum airspeed to use the windscreen wipers?",
    "answer": "80kts. (TBC ?)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0838707722723484",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "42",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum sloping ground limits with high skids and an unserviceable MMI?",
    "answer": "6° in all directions.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.591386646963656",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "43",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When is the engine overspeed protection system initiated (answer to the variant you have trained)?",
    "answer": "T2+: 114% N2 \u000bP2+: 112.9% N2.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1482339845970273",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "44",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "At what NR are a flashing ROTOR RPM warning light and continuous audio tone activated?",
    "answer": "112% and above.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7395852208137512",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "45",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum rotor RPM for application of the rotor brake?",
    "answer": "50%.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.337267090100795",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "46",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum windspeed for starting/stopping the rotors.",
    "answer": "50 kts all around",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6518551488406956",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "47",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "At what NR are a flashing ROTOR RPM warning light and continuous audio tone activated?",
    "answer": "112% and above",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.494240490719676",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "48",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum rotor RPM for application of the rotor brake?",
    "answer": "50%",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9718359527178108",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "49",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum windspeed for starting/stopping the rotors.",
    "answer": "50 kts all around",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9403341528959572",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "50",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What speed is VTOSS:",
    "answer": "40 kts",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6124080559238791",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "51",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing decision point (LDP) for a VTOL 3 approach?",
    "answer": "240'",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4186318027786911",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "52",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the typical fuel burn rate (per hour) used for planning purposes?",
    "answer": "200kg/hr",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.922457835637033",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "53",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the take-off decision point (TDP) for a clear area departure?",
    "answer": "20'/30kts",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7896485701203345",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "55",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the minimum IAS for engaging the IAS hold?",
    "answer": "60kts",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Limits",
    "weight": "0.906539452727884",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "20/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "57",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Engine start should be aborted if light-up is not achieved within what time?",
    "answer": "15 secs",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6321627511642873",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "58",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The Triple Rotor RPM Indication is a 3 pointer instrument that indicates:",
    "answer": "Main rotor RPM and power turbine speeds for both engines.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4381100665777921",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "59",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "CAD, CPDS and VEMD are abbreviations for?",
    "answer": "- Caution & Advisory Display, \u000b- Central Panel Display System\u000b- Vehicle & Engine Monitoring Display",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7085943752899766",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "60",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Cautions are displayed on the screens of the CPDS in what colour?",
    "answer": "Amber",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.561379948630929",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "61",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The MGB bay has what type of fire safety System?",
    "answer": "Has no fire detection system",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3147129509598017",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "62",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What audio/visual indications appear when the Mast Moment Indictor enters the RED range?",
    "answer": "The LIMIT symbol appears on the upper VEMD screen and the warning GONG comes on",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7930456595495342",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "63",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "During normal operation, what is the correct position of the prime pumps?",
    "answer": "On for start, Off post start.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9790647602640092",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "64",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In a OEI situation the 30” power topping function:",
    "answer": "Is the default setting. ?? TBC",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3319490952417254",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "65",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What warning is given to the pilot when approaching power band limits (5 min, 2 min & 30 second)?",
    "answer": "A LIMIT symbol with a blinking red box appears with 5 seconds to go.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8482458153739572",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "66",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The FLIGHT REPORT page automatically appears when?",
    "answer": "When the engine N1 RPM <50% and the oil pressure of the main transmission <1 bar.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4945077174343169",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "67",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The main components of the main transmission lubrication system are:",
    "answer": "Two oil pump, filler neck, oil filter, spray tubes & oil sight glass.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4193461090326308",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "68",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the the main transmission oil cooled?",
    "answer": "By two oil coolers mounted to the RH & LH side of the main transmission.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3548792316578328",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "69",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The main transmission is attached to the airframe by:",
    "answer": "- Four ARIS Dampers\u000b- One side load strut\u000b- Two torque struts",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6936006182804704",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "70",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The flexible couplings in the aft tail rotor drive shaft are installed to:",
    "answer": "Correct for misalignment and variations in length.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3774090888909996",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "71",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The rotor blades of the Fenestron are unevenly spaced for what reason?",
    "answer": "Reduces tail rotor noise.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7321958192624151",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "72",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In the event a hydraulic system 1 failure:",
    "answer": "P & R SAS will become inoperative.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1777223236858844",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "73",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The fuel transfer pumps have a dry operating time of:",
    "answer": "Approx. 20 minutes.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6531585636548698",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "74",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the foam core in the RH fuel supply tank?:",
    "answer": "Is installed to avoid a simultaneous flame out of both engines.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8188788606785239",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "75",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Power supply to the FADEC`s is made by:",
    "answer": "28V DC system and by engine mounted alternators.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5560134518891573",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "76",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In the event of an ADC2 failure, what consideration is there for NR?",
    "answer": "The HIGH NR defaults to “on” permanently and must be engaged and disengaged above and below 55 KIAS.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9698689994402228",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "77",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the P/R SAS normally selected on prior to flight?",
    "answer": "It is selected on automatically during the start sequence.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0914195333607494",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,electrical,fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "78",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does a FADEC FAIL mean/require/imply?",
    "answer": "Indicates a total failure of the control system and the pilot has the option to modulate the fuel flow with the twist grips.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0616524955257773",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "79",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In the event of a FIRE warning, when the FIRE button is released:",
    "answer": "The respective system will become “armed” but not “active” until the N1 <50%",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4288136782124639",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "80",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In normal operation, DC voltage is displayed:",
    "answer": "On VEMD 2.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8308024629950523",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "81",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Yaw SEMA 2 is only active when what other functions are engaged?",
    "answer": "Is only active with AP + A.TRIM engaged.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5576319685205817",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "82",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "To perform a pre-flight test on the Autopilot the following conditions must be fulfilled:",
    "answer": "Both engines at IDLE, collective fully down & locked and cyclic stick centred",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5671706595458089",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "83",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Engaging the Go Around mode will select:",
    "answer": "A vertical speed of 1000ft/min or 75kts depending on software.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3899022391997278",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical"
  },
  {
    "id": "84",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How many magnetic chip detectors are fitted to the MGB:",
    "answer": "1\u000b\u000bIt's located on the port side rear area of the gearbox",
    "ref": "01-28",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3189868018962443",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "85",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The maximum permitted yaw rate in the hover with HIGH NR engaged is:",
    "answer": "30°/sec",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7003952395170927",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "86",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum continuous XMSN oil temperature:",
    "answer": "105°",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7212491063401103",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "87",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The maximum airspeed with the sliding door open is:",
    "answer": "60kts.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4552411683835088",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "88",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "With a serviceable MMI what are the sloping ground limitations for a low skid aircraft:",
    "answer": "14° lateral, 12° nose up 8° nose down.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4926856164820492",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "89",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The maximum Take Off Power (5 min) FLI:",
    "answer": "10.0 up to 65kts",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3140738885849714",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "90",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The VNE OEI is:",
    "answer": "110kts.\u000b\u000bWhy?",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Unknown",
    "weight": "0.352151601575315",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "91",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the minimum transient rotor rpm power on?",
    "answer": "85%",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8035974167287349",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "92",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum continuous FLI limit with one engine in-operative:",
    "answer": "11.0",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4452800750732422",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "93",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The take-off decision point for a VTOL 2 departure is:",
    "answer": "120ft.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.365514203440398",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "94",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "VTOSS is:",
    "answer": "40kts.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5741394450888038",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "95",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Clear heliport LDP is:",
    "answer": "80ft & 40kts.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5572681720368564",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "96",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Using the attached Figure 2.3 what is the VNE with a PA of 4000ft and OAT +30°:",
    "answer": "135kts.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4547786959446967",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "97",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What speed is Vy:",
    "answer": "65kts.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7314992719329892",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "98",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Are CAT A procedures permitted with doors open?",
    "answer": "No",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6254976503551006",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "99",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Using the attached Figure D1 what is the maximum take-off and landing gross mass with an OAT of 15° and PA of 2000ft:",
    "answer": "2850kgs\u000b\u000bExam 1 paper 08/04/2020",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4530557887628674",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "100",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum operating altitude at 2720kgs:",
    "answer": "12000ft PA.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6475094915367663",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "101",
    "topic": "Mass and Loading",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The reference datum (RD) is the Station 0, it is located",
    "answer": "2160 mm forward of the levelling point",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9946304196491836",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "102",
    "topic": "Uncategorised",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Given the following parameters what is the centre of gravity of the aircraft (to nearest \u000bwhole number)?\u000bWEIGHT ARM MOMENT\u000bBASIC WT 1900 4510\u000bPILOT 80 2412\u000bCO PILOT 80 2412\u000bAFT PAX 90 4243\u000bBAGGAGE 70 5000\u000bFUEL 540 4223",
    "answer": "4337 mm",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2138570956885814",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "103",
    "topic": "Airframe",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How many fuel drains are there:",
    "answer": "4",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1072674859315156",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "104",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the engine oil contents noted?",
    "answer": "Using a sight glass on the side of the engine.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2451643594540656",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "105",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority in the event of a TRGB CHIP indication:",
    "answer": "Land as soon as practicable",
    "ref": "Card 17",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9477831111289562",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "106",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In the event of a FUEL PRESS caption illuminating in flight you should:",
    "answer": "Switch on the Prime Pumps.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1920316624455153",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "107",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "FUEL VALVE caption indicates:",
    "answer": "The Fuel Valve is in a non-commanded position.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6932319793850183",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "108",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "F QTY DEGR caption indicates:",
    "answer": "One main fuel quantity sensor has failed.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4569611600600183",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "109",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The following colour logic is used for the FCDS:",
    "answer": "Yellow for references, \u000bRed for warnings\u000bMagenta for correct ILS mode.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8289771294221282",
    "notes": "Yellow, red and magenta",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "110",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The airspeed tendency indicator gives the airspeed predicted to be reached after:",
    "answer": "5 seconds if the acceleration remains constant.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2953142561018467",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "111",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The radar height is displayed at the right side of the ND up to what height?:",
    "answer": "With a range up to 2500ft.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8933713403530419",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "112",
    "topic": "Instruments",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "With a GPS System Garmin 430 installed the wind indication will only be displayed on the ND if:",
    "answer": "“Direct to” or an active flight plan is selected.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4960402864962816",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "25/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "113",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name the 10 components of the powerplant system?",
    "answer": "- engines and engine indication system\u000b- fuel system\u000b- power management\u000b- engine starting\u000b- ignition\u000b- oil cooling system\u000b- engine mounts\u000b- firewalls\u000b- fire protection\u000b- engine drain lines",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.307474238332361",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "114",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is power management and speed control of the engines achieved?",
    "answer": "Via the FADECs",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4178240890614688",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "115",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does FADEC stand for?",
    "answer": "Full Authority Digital Engine Control",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9823413155972957",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "116",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the main fuel tank located?",
    "answer": "In the sub floor structure of the fuselage between frame 3 and 5",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7519142809323967",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "117",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the main fuel tank kept in position?",
    "answer": "Velcro strips bonded to the topside of the tank and to the underside of the cabin floor keep the tank in position",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8529722192324698",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "118",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the fuel tanks made from?",
    "answer": "Impact resistant reinforced rubberized nylon fabric.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3451162506826221",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "119",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the supply tank located?",
    "answer": "The split supply tank is located in the sub floor between frames 5 and 8.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.88106142077595",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "120",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is the certification requirement of total engine separation achieved in the context of fuel supply?",
    "answer": "The supply tank consists of 2 sections separated by a fuselage mounted fence.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3488233885727823",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "121",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the flange in the RH sidewall of the supply tank?",
    "answer": "Allows connection of an auxiliary fuel tank (option)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1703853500075638",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "122",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the flange on the RH rear top of the supply tank?",
    "answer": "This provides connection to the vent system.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2525688242167234",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "123",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the fuel expansion tank?",
    "answer": "It accommodates an increasing volume in the case of warm up.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0445982036180794",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "124",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the volume of the fuel expansion tank?",
    "answer": "Approximately 14.5 Litres",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8498523863963783",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "125",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the fuel expansion tank?",
    "answer": "Located in an aluminium box installed on the RH side of the cabin",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8038337556645273",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "126",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "What additional elements are included in the fuel vent lines in TM aircraft and why are they installed?",
    "answer": "Fuel return lines have been added to increase startup reliability with the Arrius engines.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8293612450361251",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "127",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name the 4 components of the fuel tank distribution system?",
    "answer": "- 2 main tank mounted transfer pumps\u000b- Transfer lines\u000b- 2 Supply tank mounted prime pumps\u000b- Engine feed lines with shut-off valves",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "06-12",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0873673534952104",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "128",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What guarantees that the supply tanks are always full as long as there is fuel in the main tank?",
    "answer": "The transfer pumps",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "06-12",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7520262729376553",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "129",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the dry running time for the transfer pumps?",
    "answer": "Approx 20 minutes",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "06-12",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1580357267521321",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "130",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Describe/compare the Prime Pumps with reference to the transfer pumps?",
    "answer": "The prime pumps are identical to the main tank mounted transfer pumps but there is no check valve installed in the pump outlet.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8950092368759216",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "131",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Describe how simultaneous flame out is avoided when the tanks are empty?",
    "answer": "An airframe mounted foam core is integrated into the RH supply tank which reduces the capacity by 4kg\u000b\u000bCHECK TRANSFER PUMPS are on!",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "06-12",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7566174543462693",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "132",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the 4 components of the 4 fuel equipment plates?",
    "answer": "- Fuel pump\u000b- Fuel sensor\u000b- Low fuel sensor (supply tank only)\u000b- Drain valve",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "06-14",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7133654188364744",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "133",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The fuel pumps of the main tank are each equipped with a check valve - what is the purpose of the check valve?",
    "answer": "The check valve prevents fuel from flowing back should a transfer pump fail.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "06-14",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4486178965307772",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "134",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the predetermined breaking point on the fuel sensors?",
    "answer": "In the event of a crash, they prevent the probes from penetrating the fuel cell.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Training Manual 06-14",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7554027447476982",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "135",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Can a fuel pump be replaced without defueling?",
    "answer": "Yes - the motor of the pump is mounted in a separate compartment and can be removed without defueling.",
    "ref": "06-16",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3363942708820104",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "136",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum rate of flow, in litres per minute, for gravity refueling?",
    "answer": "100 litres per minute",
    "ref": "06-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3836204926483332",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "137",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the ground connector located?",
    "answer": "Outside, LH rear side panel of the fuselage?",
    "ref": "06-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6102896854281425",
    "notes": "This is different to the 'ground socket'",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "138",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the ground socket located?",
    "answer": "It is located to the right of the filler neck. The ground socket is connected to the fuselage by a flexible ground strap.",
    "ref": "06-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9042032603174448",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "139",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the precision (shunt) resistors for the current measurement of the Transfer pumps located?",
    "answer": "On the backside of the overhead panel",
    "ref": "06-20",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1259495238773524",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "140",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Which respective busbars supply the Fwd Transfer Pump and the Aft Transfer pump?",
    "answer": "Fwd transfer pump = Essential Busbar 1\u000bAft Transfer pump = Shedding Busbar 2",
    "ref": "06-22",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8155674668960273",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "141",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Which respective busbars supply the prime pumps?",
    "answer": "Prime pump 1 = Essential Busbar 1\u000bPrime pump 2 = Essential Busbar 2",
    "ref": "06-22",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4203650550916791",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "142",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Explain how shunt resistors are used to monitor the transfer pumps and what amperage values trigger the respective CAD cautions in the Misc Field?",
    "answer": "The pumps are monitored by a shunt. When power consumption is higher than 5amps (blocked pump) or lower than 2 amps (dry running pump), for longer than 3 minutes, the caution will be triggered.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0120405368506908",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "143",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name the fuel supply components?",
    "answer": "- Engine feed lines\u000b- Shut-off valves\u000b- Switch EMERG OFF SW I\u000b- Switch EMERG OFF SW II\u000b- Circuit breaker FUEL - V ENG I\u000b- Circuit breaker FUEL - V ENG II",
    "ref": "06-26",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.896324312314391",
    "notes": "6 items",
    "created": "31/05/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "144",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What indications are shown if a EMERG OFF SW is released?",
    "answer": "- ACTIVE (warning unit) will be on continuously\u000b\u000b- FUEL VALVE on the CPDS Sys I/II displayed as long as valve is transient\u000b\u000b- F VALVE CL on the CPDS SYS I/II is displayed when the valve is closed",
    "ref": "06-26",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4411160377785564",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "145",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "If no fire warning is evident what will happen if the EMER OFF SW is operated?",
    "answer": "Only the shut-off valve will close",
    "ref": "06-26",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.616766644641757",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire"
  },
  {
    "id": "146",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Describe how fuel quantity is sensed in the aircraft?",
    "answer": "There are 4 fuel quantity transmitters. Each transmitter consists of 2 concentric tubes that form the plates of a capacitor.\u000b\u000bAs fuel level changes the value of the dielectricum - an oscillator circuit consisting of a precision resistor and the transmitter changes its freq proportional to the fuel mass in the tank. The output freq varies between 8kHz (full) and 13kHz (empty). This is processed and displayed on the CPDS",
    "ref": "06-28",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6699630292132497",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "147",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Which device carries out processing of the oscillator circuit frequency within the fuel sensors?",
    "answer": "The CAD. \u000b\u000bThe fuel sensors are directly connected to the CAD and only the CAD does the calculation.",
    "ref": "06-28",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4341108785010873",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "148",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the accuracy of fuel measurement?",
    "answer": "6% with maximum fuel content and 4% with decreasing fuel content. \u000b\u000bInaccuracies resulting from different fuel types and temperature (density) are considered within the 6% and 4% respectively.",
    "ref": "06-28",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4007971403189004",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "149",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the FUEL QTY FAIL Caution indicate?",
    "answer": "One supply tank sensor has failed or both main tank sensors have failed. \u000b\u000bThe respective bar graph will reset to 0",
    "ref": "06-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7057658261619508",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "150",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does FUEL QTY DEGR actually mean?",
    "answer": "One of the main tank sensors has failed.",
    "ref": "06-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8126008464023472",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "151",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How much fuel is available when the FUEL caution is triggered?",
    "answer": "36kg LH 32kg RH",
    "ref": "06-34",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3100513988174498",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "152",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In basic terms, how do the low fuel sensors work?",
    "answer": "Sensors fixed at a defined height and supplied with 28VDC. Fuel cools the sensor and the resistance is high resulting in a low current flow. \u000b\u000bWhen fuel is low, the sensors are exposed, they warm up, resistance reduces and the current increases and activates the LOW FUEL warning at the Warning Unit along with an audio gong every 3 seconds.",
    "ref": "06-34",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2949967393651604",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "153",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What type of resistors are the low fuel sensors and what quality do they have?",
    "answer": "NTC-thermistors - resistance reduces with heat allowing higher current flow. \u000b\u000b(resistance is normally lower at colder temperatures - at higher temperatures the atoms in the element are moving more and resisting current flow).",
    "ref": "06-34",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9716476853936912",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "154",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What does the FUEL PRESS indicate and where is it measured?",
    "answer": "It indicates low pressure between the engine driven pumps and the high pressure pumps.\u000b\u000bThe fuel pressure switch is tapped between the fuel filter outlet and the HP pump inlet.",
    "ref": "06-36",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0598968998529016",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "155",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What does the FUEL PRESS indicate and where is it measured?",
    "answer": "It indicates low pressure between the engine driven pumps and the high pressure pumps.\u000b\u000bThe fuel pressure switch is attached to the fuel management module - the pressure is tapped between the fuel filter outlet and the fuel filter inlet (?)",
    "ref": "06-36",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.095241320785135",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "157",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the FUEL FILT caution indicate?",
    "answer": "An impending opening of the by-pass due to a clogged filter. \u000b\u000bIt's a differential pressure switch.",
    "ref": "06-36",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1382238594815135",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "158",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does F FILT CT indicate?",
    "answer": "An interruption of the electrical circuit of the Fuel Filter. \u000b\u000b(ie, a break in continuity)",
    "ref": "06-36",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1216667131520807",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "159",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the reduction gearbox module?",
    "answer": "It reduces the power turbine speed (N2) to a suitable speed for the main transmission input.",
    "ref": "06-40",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8216315913014115",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "160",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is N2?",
    "answer": "Its the power turbine speed",
    "ref": "06-40",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6912645767442882",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "161",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The accessory drive gear train provides the appropriate speed reduction to turn all the engine accessories; what are the engine accessories?",
    "answer": "Starter/Generator\u000bLow pressure and high pressure fuel pumps\u000bOil pump\u000bAlternator\u000b\u000bSOFA\u000b\u000bStarter/Gen\u000bOil pumps\u000bFuel pumps\u000bAlternator",
    "ref": "06-40",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3187575312331319",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "162",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where does air enter the engine?",
    "answer": "Via a radial inlet plenum chamber",
    "ref": "06-40",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2325155041180551",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "163",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "How many fuel nozzles are there?",
    "answer": "2 x start nozzles\u000b10 x main nozzles",
    "ref": "06-42",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3072964292950928",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "164",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What components are cooled and lubricated by the engine oil system?",
    "answer": "Reduction gear train\u000bAccessory gear train\u000bCentrifugal compressor front bearing\u000bCompressor turbine rear bearings\u000bPower turbine front bearing",
    "ref": "06-44",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0913593894802034",
    "notes": "5 items",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "165",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "What does the oil system consist of?",
    "answer": "Integral oil tank\u000bPressure system\u000bScavenge system\u000bBreather system\u000bIndication",
    "ref": "06-44",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9371508690528572",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "166",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "Describe the location and installation of the oil tank?",
    "answer": "The oil tank is integral with the engine - it is formed by the lower sump of the reduction gearbox.",
    "ref": "06-44",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1511308467015624",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "167",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "After providing lubrication, how is oil returned to the sump?",
    "answer": "By gravity\u000b\u000b(The sump is at the bottom of the reduction gearbox)",
    "ref": "06-44",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.992157504428178",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "168",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the scavenge pumps?",
    "answer": "Oil cooling - After the oil returns to the sump by gravity, it is immediately drawn away from the pump via the scavenge pumps to the cooling unit and returned to the tank.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8855405393987894",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "169",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What specific components are the strainers in the oil system protecting?",
    "answer": "They protect the scavenge pumps against any particles which may be contained in the lubrication oil.",
    "ref": "06-44",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2824379582889378",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "170",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Name the components of the Engine Fuel System?",
    "answer": "Fuel pump unit\u000bFuel filter\u000bFuel metering unit\u000bValve assembly\u000bInjection system\u000bFADEC\u000bIndication",
    "ref": "06-46",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3688673404976725",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "171",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the Fuel Pump unit?",
    "answer": "Supplies fuel at certain conditions of pressure and flow and is mounted on the front face of the reduction gearboxand driven by the N1 gear-train",
    "ref": "06-46",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1216919971629977",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "172",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Describe the engine Fuel Pump Unit?",
    "answer": "It is mounted on the front face of the reduction gearbox and driven by the N1 geartrain.\u000b\u000bConsists of a LP centrifugal pump, HP gear type pump. \u000b\u000bA PRV in the HP pump outlet opens in case of excessive pressure and relieves fuel back to the inlet port of the HP pump.",
    "ref": "06-46",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0281171542592346",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "173",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "Where is the fuel filter in relation to the aircraft engine?",
    "answer": "Mounted on the front face of the reduction gearbox.",
    "ref": "06-46",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2484454824589193",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "174",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "Where in the system is the fuel filter?",
    "answer": "The fuel filter is between the LP pump outlet and HP pump inlet",
    "ref": "06-46",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9763292423449456",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "175",
    "topic": "Airframe",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "How is the fuel filter monitored for blockage?",
    "answer": "The fuel filter is monitored by an impending bypass switch for cockpit indication as well as by a mechanical blockage indicator at the filter housing.",
    "ref": "06-46",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7471160311251879",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "176",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "Where is the fuel metering unit installed?",
    "answer": "On the front face of the reduction gearbox.",
    "ref": "06-48",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0166441169567406",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "177",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "What are the 2 basic modes of the Fuel Metering unit and how is each controlled?",
    "answer": "1 - Automatic mode:- the metering valve is controlled by a stepper motor which is commanded by the EECU (FADEC)\u000b\u000b2 - Manual Mode: In manual mode the metering valve is controlled by a control lever, actuated by the collective twist grip.",
    "ref": "06-48",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.984965793788433",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "178",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "In the context of the Fuel Metering Unit, what is 'Mixed Mode'?",
    "answer": "Mixed mode is activated when the twist grip is moved out of the neutral position. In this mode the metering is controlled by the twist grip and the stepper motor at the same time. The pilots input will be counteracted by the EECU as there is no malfunction. \u000b------------------------------------------------\u000b\u000bThere is no mixed mode with P - any movement of the twist grip out of the neutral position results in an immediate switch to manual with TWIST GRIP and ENGINE MANUAL on the CPDS",
    "ref": "06-48",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6320546832866967",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "179",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What features does the FMU (fuel metering unit) provide?",
    "answer": "- Enables engine start and shutdown\u000b- Controls fuel flow according to demand\u000b- No power change during transition from EECU mode to manual mode\u000b- Full power selection range available in manual mode as well as EECU mode\u000b- Limits acceleration and decelerationto prevent surge and flame-out during manual control mode.",
    "ref": "06-48",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7161369696259499",
    "notes": "Think about different circumstances",
    "created": "03/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "180",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What is the general purpose of the fuel valve assembly?",
    "answer": "The fuel valve assembly delivers metered fuel from the FMU to the injection system",
    "ref": "06-50",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9553253608755768",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "181",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Where is the fuel valve assembly located?",
    "answer": "It is located on the upper part of the combustion chamber casing",
    "ref": "06-50",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5772130470722914",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "182",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "What are the 5 valves within the Fuel Valve Assembly?",
    "answer": "- Start electro valve (dist F to injectors)\u000b\u000b- Stop electro valve (controls flow to injectors)\u000b\u000b- Injector distribution valve (controls fuel flow in general)\u000b\u000b- Stop purge valve (purges injectors to prevent carbonisation\u000b\u000b- Pressurising Valve (during start ensures priority of fuel to start injectors)",
    "ref": "06-50",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3903461284935474",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "183",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "How many injectors are there in the injection system?",
    "answer": "9 Main injectors mounted around the combustion chambers and 1 preference injector.\u000b\u000bAdditionally there are 2 start injectors mounted at 1 o'clock and 9 o'clock around the combustion chamber.",
    "ref": "06-50",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9968618550337852",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "185",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Describe the co-ordination of the start injectors with the main injectors?",
    "answer": "Only the start injectors deliver fuel during start - at 50%N1 the start electro valves closes flow to the start injectors. Meanwhile the injector distribution valve is open and the main injector together with the preference injector deliver fuel to the combustion chamber.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9456120072863996",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "186",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the preference injector?",
    "answer": "If during normal operation the fuel flow is reduced significantly, the injector distribution valve closes the but the preference injector still delivers fuel to the combustion chamber to avoid an engine flame out.",
    "ref": "06-50",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.128791463561356",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "187",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "How is torque measured?",
    "answer": "The angular displacement of the output shaft is measured against the reference shaft via an electromagnetic sensor, ie a phonic wheel arrangement. This creates a pulsed voltage which is sent to the EECU(T2) or EEC(P2)",
    "ref": "06-52 / 06-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5272017028182745",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "188",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Where is Tq measured from?",
    "answer": "In front of the reduction gearbox near the output shaft.",
    "ref": "06-52",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3607114399783312",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "189",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Where does the EECU send the processed Tq signal?",
    "answer": "To the CPDS in the cockpit to show % Tq",
    "ref": "06-52",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9061221582815052",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "10/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "190",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the Tq confirmation box?",
    "answer": "It compensates for material and manufacturing tolerances as each output shaft will be different. These are unique and calibrated to each shaft therefore the confirmation box cannot be transferred to another engine? \u000b\u000bThe Pratt & Whitney system is called a DCU (Data Collection Unit) which does a similar task.",
    "ref": "06-52 and 06-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4279887517914176",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "191",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "Why can't the Tq confirmation box be transferred to another engine?",
    "answer": "Because no two output shafts will twist in the same manner therefore each confirmation box is tuned to a specific engine output shaft.",
    "ref": "06-52",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7613594140857458",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "192",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "At which location is gas temperature measured?",
    "answer": "Gas generator turbine outlet. 4 identical temperature double sensors are located around the rear part of the combustion chamber housing.",
    "ref": "06-54",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4991534627042711",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "11/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "193",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "Four identical double sensors measure gas turbine temperature around the rear part of the combusion chamber casing. Where are the measurement signals sent?",
    "answer": "One set supplies a signal to the indication system\u000b\u000bThe other 4 parallel thermo elements provide signals direct to the FADEC box.",
    "ref": "06-54",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.954933067318052",
    "notes": "Sent to 2 locations",
    "created": "11/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "194",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "CPDS Indication of Gas Turbine - where does the corrected value of Gas Turbine appear?",
    "answer": "FLI",
    "ref": "06-54",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0763282692059874",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "11/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "195",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "CPDS Indication of Gas Turbine - with one line of the respective TOT indication in the FLI lost, where else can TOT value be found?",
    "answer": "The non-corrected TOT value is shown is displayed in the SYSTEM STATUS page.",
    "ref": "06-54",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0100009804591536",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "11/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "196",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "How many fuel nozzles are there and how is this different to the T2?",
    "answer": "The P2 has 12 fuel nozzles- the T2 has 10 main fuel nozzles and 2 starter nozzles",
    "ref": "06-60",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5670567862689495",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "197",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the cold start valve and where is it located?",
    "answer": "The cold start valve is located at the pressure pump outlet and safeguards against excessive pressure build up due to high viscosity at low temperatures. It limits the pressure to 13.5bar (200 psi)",
    "ref": "06-62",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4112740312702954",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "198",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the P3 operated shut off valve?",
    "answer": "It prevents oil supply to the lubrication points upon startup and at shutdown <40%n1. This ensures the remote bearing cavities do not flood during motoring or rundown periods.",
    "ref": "06-62",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0272512137889862",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "199",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "How does the oil tank differ between the P2 and the T2?",
    "answer": "T2 oil tank is integral with the engine and is formed by a sump at the bottom of the reduction gearbox.\u000b\u000bThe P2 is a dry sump system and the tank is formed by the annular cavity created between the air inlet case and the reduction gearbox.",
    "ref": "06-62",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2996141063049436",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "200",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "Describe the journey of a particle of oil from the tank, back to the tank?",
    "answer": "Oil is drawn from the tank\u000bThrough a screen\u000bpressure pump\u000bPasses through oil filter\u000bPasses through oil heater\u000bDistributed to gearbox and bearings\u000bScavenge pump returns oil to gearbox\u000bGearbox scavenge pump draws oil from the sump via a screenand chip detector\u000bOil then flows through cooler\u000bReturned to oil tank.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.249931217636913",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "201",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the fuel heater and when does it operate?",
    "answer": "It is installed between the pump outlet and the filter inlet. At fuel temperatures below 43deg Ca temperature controlled bypass valve is closed and the fuel has to flow through the heater.\u000b\u000bAbove 57 deg C the valve is fully open and the heater is by-passed.",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8943659937940539",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "202",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the Fuel Flow Divider?",
    "answer": "It distributes metered fuel flow from the Fuel Management Module to the primary and secondary side of the fuel manifold?",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8016455047763885",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "203",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What does the fuel flow divider do during start?",
    "answer": "The fuel flow divider routes fuel flow to the hybrid nozzles only. As the engine accelerates, fuel pressure increases and the flow divider routes fuel to the main nozzles also.\u000b\u000bThe T2+ has starter injectors as well as main injectors and a preference injector",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.99735913798213",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "204",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "How does the fuel flow divider prevent accumulation of fuel in the combustion chamber after shut down?",
    "answer": "Residual fuel is kept in an accumulator - at next start as fuel pressure increases, a piston forces the fuel towards the manifold",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0738405780866742",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "205",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the Fuel Manifold?",
    "answer": "It distributes primary (start) and secondary (main) fuel to the engine combustion chamber.\u000b\u000bIt is located on the engine gas generator case\u000b\u000bIn the T2 the analogous system is called the Fuel Valve Assembly.",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7339053996838629",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "206",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "Describe the arrangement of fuel nozzles?",
    "answer": "The primary fuel manifold supplies 5 hybrid nozzles. \u000bThe secondary fuel manifold supplies 7 main fuel nozzles\u000bThe fuel nozzles are equally spaced around the combustion chamber for even fuel flow.",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3964150599204004",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "207",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "True or false - primary fuel only flows during start up?",
    "answer": "False - primary fuel flow from the primary nozzles remains constant during start-up and engine operation.",
    "ref": "06-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6402572225779295",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "208",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What does FMM stand for and what is its purpose?",
    "answer": "Fuel Management Module - it works in conjunction with the EEC to control metered fuel flow over the entire operational range of the engine.\u000b\u000bIn theTraining Manual - the equivalent T2 component would be the FMU - Fuel Metering Unit.",
    "ref": "06-68",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4459243114106356",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "209",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What are the inputs/parameters in to the FMM?",
    "answer": "EEC signals\u000bTwist grip angle\u000bP3 pressure\u000bNg speed",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8145376485772432",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "210",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What modes does the FMM operate in?",
    "answer": "2 basic mode:\u000b\u000bAutomatic Mode - the EEC controls the tq motor which rotates the fuel metering valve\u000b\u000bManual Mode - the fuel metering valve is controlled by 3D-Cam actuated by the twist grip.",
    "ref": "06-68",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6527467318810523",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "17/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "211",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is torque shaft temperature compensated for?",
    "answer": "A platinum-type temperature measurement resistor located in the Torque sensor provide compensation for variation of torque shaft temperature. \u000b\u000bThe sensor is mounted in front of the reduction gearbox near the output shaft.",
    "ref": "06-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0204524798318743",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "212",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "Describe the gas temperature measuring system?",
    "answer": "It consists of 2 identical harnesses with 4 thermocouple elements in parallel connected to an engine mounted terminal assembly.",
    "ref": "06-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8508839663118124",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "213",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 2 junction boxes in the gas temperature measuring system?",
    "answer": "They provide the signal from the 8 sensors (4 each in parallel) to the inlet temperature sensor box",
    "ref": "06-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.070640976075083",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "214",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the inlet temperature sensor box in the gas temperature measuring system?",
    "answer": "The inlet temperature sensor box combines the T6 signals with the signal from the T1 sensor.",
    "ref": "06-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5558733204379678",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "215",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "Where is the T1 sensor measured and where is the signal sent?",
    "answer": "The T1 temperature is measured at the compressor air inlet thereby giving a signal proportional to engine air inlet temperature. \u000b\u000bThe signals provided by the T1 and T6 sensors are sent to the EEC where the measured gas temperature (MGT) is computed.",
    "ref": "06-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7430724748410285",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "216",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "Describe the CPDS indication for engine temperature?",
    "answer": "The digital TOT is sent from the EEC to the FLI (eng 1 via VEMD lane 1 and eng 2 via VEMD lane 2.\u000b\u000bIn the case of 1 lane off, the respective back-up analogue value is displayed on the CAD.",
    "ref": "06-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6482749502174556",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "18/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "217",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 002",
    "answer": "Aircraft starting procedures including hand signals and external panel checks etc",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1560591422021389",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "218",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 003",
    "answer": "Laser Incidents and actions to take. \u000b\u000bInitial response is a dynamic risk assessment to weigh up the task against the need to prosecute offenders for laser beam strike. \u000b\u000bDo not look at the laser\u000b\u000bContinue with laser goggles or abandon the task\u000b\u000bInform ATC\u000bInform Ops Centre\u000b\u000bNVG offer protection due to a displayed image rather than actual laser light",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4552456275559962",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "219",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 004?",
    "answer": "Fuel Storage and management",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7592781423591077",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "220",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 005?",
    "answer": "Mobile Fuel Bowser",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5014404077082872",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "221",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 006?",
    "answer": "Adverse weather actions;\u000b\u000bHeavy rain, thunderstorms, strong winds, snow and ice, ice clearance. \u000b\u000bIce clearance plans are detailed for each base.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0117582743987441",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "222",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 007?",
    "answer": "Bird Safeguarding\u000b\u000bBrief description of bird migration patterns and the need for risk to aircraft. \u000b\u000bSite/base specific are listed.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8886748855002224",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "223",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 009?",
    "answer": "NPAS & Airbus maintenance communications SOP, \u000b\u000beg, during working hours, out of working hours etc.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3720858027227223",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "224",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 008?",
    "answer": "Details the risk and examples of FOD\u000bDetails procedures to be followed if FOD is found\u000b\u000bThis SOP also details the requirement for the day duty crew to carry out a FOD plod. \u000b\u000bFOD damage and actions to take as a result of damage due to adverse weather is also contained here.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6319130826741457",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "225",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 011?",
    "answer": "Use of Helilift",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7816591989248991",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "226",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 013?",
    "answer": "Driving and Use of NPAS Vehicles",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9396902141161264",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "227",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 014?",
    "answer": "Helicopter open door procedure\u000b\u000bSOP to be read in conjunction with Petzel Aircraft Harness and Lanyard SOP\u000bThis SOP also contains Challenge and response procedure between TFO and pilot.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2943163653835654",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "228",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 015?",
    "answer": "Document control\u000b\u000bPretty dull SOP about NPAS document management.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5970224803313613",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "229",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 016?",
    "answer": "Covid and use of Skyshout",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1210904689505696",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "230",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 017?",
    "answer": "Building Inspections\u000b\u000bBasically - facilities management.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4840357680805028",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "231",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 018?",
    "answer": "Helicopter cleaning",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5853916192427278",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "232",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 019?",
    "answer": "Management of CVFDR Data post accident/incident.\u000b\u000bUnder EU regulation 965/2012 it is the responsibility of the operator and the commander of the aircraft to preserve the recordings of the FDR and CVR following a reportable incident or accident until otherwise directed by the AAIB.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7895829225890337",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "233",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 020?",
    "answer": "Helmet acquirement, maintenance and disposal.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8598064002580941",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "234",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 021?",
    "answer": "Evidential media",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8332979781553149",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "235",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 022?",
    "answer": "Airborne DataLink\u000b\u000bOverview of datalink, datalink channels, channel conflict and interference, national channel plan etc",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2644740999676287",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "236",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 023?",
    "answer": "Maintenance Check flights\u000b\u000bFormal check flights are specified by the aircraft manufacturer and normally included in the maintenance programme. \u000b\u000bCAMSO will be informed. \u000b\u000bThere are Level A and Level B check flights\u000b\u000bNPAS pilots will rarely be required to complete a Maintenance Check Flight (MCF)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8155628922395408",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "237",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 024?",
    "answer": "EFB Policy \u000b\u000bExtensive guidance on the EFB and its use.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8347507314756512",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "238",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 025?",
    "answer": "CCTV\u000b\u000bSurveillance systems at the base.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7042793054133654",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "239",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 026?",
    "answer": "NVIS Maintenance Repair and Control",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7835916895419358",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "240",
    "topic": "NPAS SOPs",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is contained in NPAS SOP 027?",
    "answer": "Management of W&B Schedules and Updating Easyweigh",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Centrik",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3895674971863627",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "19/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "241",
    "topic": "Avionics",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What aerial is showing the picture?",
    "answer": "VOR/ILS",
    "ref": "02-12",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.0090089603327214",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "242",
    "topic": "Avionics",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 3 aerials are showing in this picture?",
    "answer": "ELT - Forward (right of picture)\u000b?? - Middle\u000bTransponder/TCAS (TBC) - Aft",
    "ref": "02-12",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4209591927938163",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "243",
    "topic": "Avionics",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 2 aerials are showing in this picture?",
    "answer": "VHF-AM2 - Upper\u000bILS/VOR lower horizontal aerial",
    "ref": "02-12",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4952129069715738",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "244",
    "topic": "Avionics",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 2 aerials are showing in this picture?",
    "answer": "VHF 1 - Fwd TBC ??\u000b?? Aft",
    "ref": "02-12",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9191673793829976",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "245",
    "topic": "Avionics",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What aerial is shown in this picture?",
    "answer": "ILS Marker Beacon Receiver",
    "ref": "02-12",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7239569220691918",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "246",
    "topic": "Avionics",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What aerial is shown in this picture?",
    "answer": "Tac 5",
    "ref": "02-12",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.3789825895801186",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "247",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The aircraft is equipped with electronic engine control. What 2 acronyms are used by PW and TM respectively for this?",
    "answer": "PW = EEC\u000bTM = EECU",
    "ref": "06-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4344877768307924",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical"
  },
  {
    "id": "248",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the EEC/EECU achieve in terms of fuel consumption?",
    "answer": "It keeps fuel consumption to a minimum whilst adjusting/optimising engine power for the flight profile.",
    "ref": "06-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6444488354027271",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "249",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What functions of engine control do the EEC/EECU provide?",
    "answer": "Starting\u000bGround operation\u000bFlight\u000bCPDS\u000bManual emergency control\u000b\u000bSee 'Get more Info' for a schematic diagram and more details",
    "ref": "06-80",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5865806667134166",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "250",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Make a simple statement to describe what the FADEC does and, ultimately, achieves?",
    "answer": "The FADEC is digitally controls the engine to give the right power and speed to the rotor system.",
    "ref": "06-80",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8626097831875085",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "251",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the FADECs located?",
    "answer": "below the engine deck in the middle section of the fuselage between frame 5 and 6",
    "ref": "06-80",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0056655597873032",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "252",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "List the specific functions of the FADEC",
    "answer": "Automatic start of the engines\u000bFuel supply\u000bAutomatic engine control in all RPMM and power ranges\u000bMonitoring of engines and power parameters\u000bLimitation of fuel after topping parameters have been reached\u000bOverspeed protection\u000bTraining Mode\u000bCAT A / High NR\u000bTopping Selection\u000bTorque Matching\u000bFault Detection",
    "ref": "06-80",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1688151038251817",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "253",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When does the DC system supply electrical power to the FADEC?",
    "answer": "During engine starting (up to 35-40% N1) or failure of the engine alternator/PMA",
    "ref": "06-82",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2844255599193275",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "254",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "On the ground, with engines not running, how is power supply to the FADEC achieved?",
    "answer": "Via the DC essential busbars and with the switches on the engine control panel closed.",
    "ref": "06-82",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0134133649989962",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "255",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "In flight, what would happen if a FADEC switch was opened on the Engine Control panel?",
    "answer": "The FADEC would remain operative with the alternator supplying power - the FADEC would be disconnected from the DC system only and the caution REDUND would appear on the CPDS",
    "ref": "06-82",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9281330322846768",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "256",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When will the starter control relay disconnect the ignition circuit?",
    "answer": "After attaining self-sustaining speed of 50% N1",
    "ref": "06-84",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3066492429934442",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "257",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How can the engine be controlled manually?",
    "answer": "By switching the overhead panel NORM/MAN switch to manual",
    "ref": "06-86",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0461805439554154",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "258",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What N2 speed datum is set when the engine start switch is selected to FLIGHT?",
    "answer": "The N2 speed datum is set to 100% under normal flight conditions",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1278690043836832",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "259",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What N2 speed datum is automatically set between 4000' DA and 9000'?",
    "answer": "104%",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0683776987716555",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "260",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Is the pilot able to adjust engine Torque?",
    "answer": "Yes - with the ENG TRIM switch:\u000b\u000bL+ inc eng 1 and dec eng 2\u000bR+ Inc power eng 2 and decrease power eng 1",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8034284319728613",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "261",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the ENG TRIM switch demands processed?",
    "answer": "In the engine EEC/EECU",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5013095545582473",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "262",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What device is used to compensate for Droop (ie, a momentary decrease in NR)?",
    "answer": "An LVDT (linear transducer) sends a signal to the EEC/EECU to anticipate the power/fuel damand when collective is raised or the left pedal pushed.",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6575398193672299",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "263",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How many LVDTs are there?",
    "answer": "2 - one for each engine - they are arranged such that collective and pedal input are superimposed to give a combined LVDT output. \u000b\u000bLVDT = Linear Variable Differential Transformer. The unit itself can be generically referred to as a 'transducer'.",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0361233623698353",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "264",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What features are available via the cross-talk capability of the EEC/EECU?",
    "answer": "Manual Mode\u000bOEI Situation\u000bTraining Mode Activation\u000bAutomatic bleed air shut-off during OEI\u000bAutomatic Torque matching",
    "ref": "06-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4945107689127326",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "265",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What are the normal Power ON Nr limits?",
    "answer": "97 - 104%",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.36401833826676",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "266",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What are the power OFF Nr limits?",
    "answer": "85 - 106%",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.018303305376321",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "267",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the upper and lower transient NR limits and for how long?",
    "answer": "112 and 85 for 20 seconds\u000b\u000b112 = continuous tone and flashing light",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2930188328027724",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "268",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the AEO take off FLI and Tq limit?",
    "answer": "FLI 10\u000b78% Tq\u000b\u000b(little tip for remembering transient figures - 'add 4' = Fli 10.4 and 82% Tq",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.534994475543499",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "14/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "269",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the transient AEO limits and for how long?",
    "answer": "FLI 10.4\u000b82% Tq\u000b\u000b10 seconds\u000b\u000bunintended V - Vy only.",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5266102710738778",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "270",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the max continuous OEI FLI and Tq limits?",
    "answer": "FLI 11\u000bTq 89.5",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9971427018754184",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "271",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the 2 min power OEI limit? (FLI and Tq)",
    "answer": "FLI 13\u000bTq 125%",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5819387556985021",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "272",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the 30 sec power OEI limit? (FLI and Tq)",
    "answer": "FLI 13.5\u000bTq 128%",
    "ref": "Card 28",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6698275725357234",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "273",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum all up mass?",
    "answer": "2910kgs",
    "ref": "Card 29",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7784539451822639",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "274",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the total fuel capacity?",
    "answer": "568 kg",
    "ref": "Card 29",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5918211662210524",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "275",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the unusable fuel?",
    "answer": "7.6 kgs",
    "ref": "Card 29",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1342880595475435",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "276",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the Police MLA (day and night)?",
    "answer": "70kg - Day\u000b90kg - NIght",
    "ref": "Card 29",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.249046656768769",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "277",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What mean fuel level does the FUEL LOW light illuminate?",
    "answer": "24 kgs (26 / 22kgs)",
    "ref": "Card 29",
    "source": "FRCs P2",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7957002329640089",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "278",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "High NR mode will be deactivated above what speed and activated below what speed respectively?",
    "answer": "Exceeding 55kts and automatically activated below 50 kts",
    "ref": "06-92",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8255202621221542",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "279",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum Tq delivery that the engine control system will allow?",
    "answer": "133% Tq to protect the MGB in critical flight situations",
    "ref": "06-98",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9185424828901888",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "280",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the normal Tq limit of the Tq limiter for the 30 sec rating?",
    "answer": "128%",
    "ref": "06-98",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4431621027179062",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "281",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "At what N2 will the overspeed protection be activated?",
    "answer": "114% +/- 1%N2 - the EECU then commands the shut-off valve to close which causes an engine to shut down.\u000b\u000b(This is slightly different to the P2)",
    "ref": "06-24",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9572811829857528",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "282",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "At what N2 will the overspeed protection activate and what does the activation initiate?",
    "answer": "The overspeed will be activated when N2 is greater than 112.9 %.\u000b\u000bThe system reduces engine fuel flow in a controlled manner. As soon as the reset RPM is reached, the fuel flow returns to a standard fuel flow control. \u000b\u000b(In the T2 the engine is shutdown)",
    "ref": "06-106",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8676623771898448",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "283",
    "topic": "Differences",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the respective engine pressure start (2 mins) limits?",
    "answer": "P2+ = 0 - 13.8 bar\u000b\u000bT2+ = 10 - 15 bar",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.774192766752094",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "284",
    "topic": "Differences",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the minimum engine oil pressure?",
    "answer": "P2+ = 2.1 bar\u000b\u000bT2+ = 1.3 bar",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9451722288504244",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "285",
    "topic": "Differences",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the continuous engine oil pressure?",
    "answer": "P2+ = 4 to 8.5 bar\u000b\u000bT2+ = 1.3 to 5 bar",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7257612035609781",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "286",
    "topic": "Differences",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the continuous engine oil temperature?",
    "answer": "P2+ = 10 to 129.5 deg\u000b\u000bT2+ = 10 to 110 deg",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5353746828623116",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "287",
    "topic": "Differences",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the engine oil pressure caution range?",
    "answer": "P2+ = 2.1 to 4 bar\u000bT2+ = 5 to 10 bar",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1183563400991261",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "288",
    "topic": "Differences",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the max engine oil temperature and pressure?",
    "answer": "P2+ = 13.8 bar and 129.5 deg\u000bT2+ = 10 bar and and 110 deg",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.576883596368134",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "289",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum XMSN pressure and temperature?",
    "answer": "10 bar and 120 deg",
    "ref": "Card 28 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6342888316139579",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "27/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "290",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "What are the 3 cockpit indications to inform the pilot that the FADEC is in a faulty condition?",
    "answer": "REDUND. Minor fault - loss of protection or secondary function eg, loss of 1 power supply\u000b\u000b\u000bDEGRADE. Reduced engine performance - full N2 governing is maintained\u000b\u000b\u000bFADEC FAIL. Total fail of the control system (frozen stepper motor. Fuel flow is now fixed - pilot can either leave it fixed or use the twist grip to modulate the fuel flow. \u000b\u000bSee Question 291 for P differences",
    "ref": "06-106",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7767399102449417",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "291",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What are the 2 cockpit indications to inform the pilot that the FADEC is in a faulty condition?",
    "answer": "FADEC MINR. \u000bA change or loss of governing functions. May result in degraded engine operating. Full N2 governing is maintained\u000b\u000b\u000bFADEC FAIL\u000bControl system is not operating. System reverts* to manual mode. The Tq motor in the Fuel Metering unit is inhibited ad fuel flow is fixed. \u000b\u000bPilot then controls manually.\u000b*\"Revert\" is from the manual - not sure if this implies some kind of automatic switching etc\u000b\u000bSee Question 290 for T differences",
    "ref": "06-106",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2876535416580736",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "292",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "During EC135 development what was the first development of stabilisation augmentation?",
    "answer": "Yaw - SA. Later, pitch and roll SAS systems and a pitch damper were installed",
    "ref": "05-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.456112967338413",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "293",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The SAS systems form a modular structure and of different technical design but they normally work together to create a system with how many axis?",
    "answer": "A 3-axis SAS system",
    "ref": "05-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8869508039206265",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "294",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What type of actuators does the SAS system employ?",
    "answer": "Series actuators - ie, in series with the pilots controls.",
    "ref": "05-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5461349762044847",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "295",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What switches on the overhead panel need to be closed (tuned on) for the SAS to be active?",
    "answer": "The 3-axis SAS system is fully operative if the inverter is active and avionic master switches are engaged.",
    "ref": "05-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9981725565157832",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "296",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name the generic items in the YAW SAS system for detection and actuation and the type of data system used?",
    "answer": "A Yaw FOG is used for detection, SEMA 1 for actuation and the data type is ARINC 429\u000b\u000bThe Yaw Fog is in the tail boom between frame 7 and 8. The computation of the signals from the Fog is done by the SEMA. There is no device between. 04-78",
    "ref": "05-18",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4596695839427412",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "297",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What type of actuators are used in the Pitch and Roll SAS system?",
    "answer": "Electro Hydraulic Actuators (EHA) - commands are given by a Pitch and Roll SAS computer in analogue signals.",
    "ref": "05-20",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8085375619120896",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "298",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Why does the AHRS system need to be able to generate analogue signals?",
    "answer": "The P/R SAS computer is old technology - it's a legacy requirement from when rate gyros created analaogue signals. Therefore the AHRS1 creates analogue rate gyro signals if the inverter is switched on. (for input into the EHAs)",
    "ref": "05-20",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0818767766468226",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "299",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What aspect of the SAS system needs to be installed for dual pilot IFR certification?",
    "answer": "An additional pitch damper in order to compensate for excessive pitch changes.",
    "ref": "05-22",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.859837326221168",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "300",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name the basic components of the Pitch Damper SAS system?",
    "answer": "Pitch FOG and Pitch SEMA\u000b\u000bThe Pitch SEMA sends limited control signals to the Pitch EHA (so there is some integration of the 'old system' with the 'new system'. \u000b\u000bA pitch runaway of the EHA will be sensed by the Pitch Damper and the situation recovered. \u000b\u000bThe schematic design of the Pitch Damper is very similar to the Yaw SAS system",
    "ref": "05-22",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3349781851284205",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "301",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What problem/malfunction within the SAS system could the Pitch Damper delay/mitigate?",
    "answer": "The pitch SEMA can also delay the effect of a (unlikely) runaway of the pitch EHA.",
    "ref": "05-22",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6592504153959453",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "302",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What type of data control signals are transmitted to the PITCH damper SEMA from the PITCH Damper FOG?",
    "answer": "ARINC 429",
    "ref": "05-22",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8018943369388579",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "303",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the red button on the top left of the cyclic do?",
    "answer": "All systems belonging to the SAS and AFCS are deactivated via this button.",
    "ref": "05-24",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3487838613800704",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "304",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The EC135 AFCS consists of what 3 sub-systems?",
    "answer": "3-axis SAS\u000bPitch Damper\u000bAutopilot",
    "ref": "05-26",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3655313509516418",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "305",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 2 components does the AP consist of and what additional actuators are installed?",
    "answer": "The Autopilot Module (APM 2000)\u000band the Autopilot Mode Selector.\u000b\u000bFor additional control authority and redundancy a roll SEMA and Yaw SEMA (2) are installed",
    "ref": "05-26",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1330222967080772",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "306",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name as many of the 13 services that the autopilot system provides?",
    "answer": "- Digital SAS (AP SAS)\u000b- Auto Trim (A. Trim)\u000b- Heading Hold (HDG)\u000b- Altitude Hold (ALT)\u000b- Airspeed Hold (IAS)\u000b- Vertical Speed Hold (VIS)\u000b- Altitude Acquire (ALT.A)\u000b- VOR Navigation (NAV VOR)\u000b- Long Range Navigation (NAV NMS)\u000b- Localiser Mode (LOC)\u000b- VOR approach mode (APP VOR.A)\u000b- Glideslope (G/S)\u000b- Go Around mode (GA)",
    "ref": "05-26",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9567904737778008",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "307",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the APM Located?",
    "answer": "Integrated in the Pelican Rack on the avionics deck",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1859469129703939",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "308",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the ADCs?",
    "answer": "ADC 1/2 are installed respectively in the LH and RH channels of the helicopter (lower fuselage area)",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1055442243814468",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "309",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the pitch FOG?",
    "answer": "Installed in the LH channel of the helicopter. Operates in the longitudinal axix and provides signals to the pitch damper SEMA",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8196732494980096",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "310",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the yaw fog?",
    "answer": "aft, upper section of the cargo compartment near to the rear attachment cone. It gives yaw rate signals to Yaw SEMA 1",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5595163321122527",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "311",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the APMS?",
    "answer": "The autopilot mode selector is integrated below the instrument panel in the slant console.",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0758355176076292",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "312",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the Pitch & Roll SAS Computer?",
    "answer": "LH side channel of the helicopter. It uses signals from AHRS 1 to compute the stabilising input signals for the EHA.",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3451564498245716",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "313",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the Roll SEMA?",
    "answer": "Roll axis control rod directly in front of the hydraulic actuator",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.437136824708432",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "314",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the Yaw SEMA?",
    "answer": "Mounted on each end of the control rod for the Fenestron servo actuator.",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0236829500645399",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "315",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When is the Yaw SEMA 2 active?",
    "answer": "Yaw SEMA 2 is only active with AP + A.Trim enagaged.",
    "ref": "05-30",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6682031047530472",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "316",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the EHAs located?",
    "answer": "They are installed directly in the hydraulics of the main rotor actuator",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6382203339599073",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "317",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the Trim Motors (parallel actuators) located?",
    "answer": "Below the cabin floor in the forward section of the helicopter",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8306935061700642",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "318",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the FCDM 1/2 located?",
    "answer": "The Flight Control Display Modules are located in the Pelican Rack in the avionics deck",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8572483104653656",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "319",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the LVDT Pedal located?",
    "answer": "Mounted directly on the pilots pedal structure below the cabin floor.",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7890762370079757",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "320",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the LVDT on the pedal structure do for the APM?",
    "answer": "It measures the pilots pedal position sends this information to the APM which is used to detect a pilots override of the pedal controls.",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2032194505445659",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "321",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where is the LVDT Collective located and what does it do?",
    "answer": "Below the floor in the centre section. It provides one of the conditions \"in flight\" or \"helicopter on ground\". It also acts as an anticipator which enables the AP to react faster to minimise the influence of collective movements on other axis.",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3352912398986518",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "322",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the AHRS located?",
    "answer": "The AHRS 1/2 are installed below the floor in the centre section of the helicopter. They comprise 3-axis fibre optical gyros and accelerometers.",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.29154650028795",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "323",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where are the Magnetometers located?",
    "answer": "They are installed in the tail boom. They give a reference to magnetic north.",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.172102740034461",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "324",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What and where is the DTS?",
    "answer": "This is the connection receptacle for the test equipment of the AFCS system - it's integrated on the circuit breaker panel  of the high load bus 1.",
    "ref": "05-32",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0331104011274874",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "325",
    "topic": "SAS+Autopilot",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the inverter connected to?",
    "answer": "P/R SAS Computer as well as the AHRS 1.\u000b\u000bThe AHRS1 is the signal source for the P&R SAS computer and needs an analogue signal",
    "ref": "05-34",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2119289287365973",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "28/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "326",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the recommended speed for autorotation?",
    "answer": "75kts",
    "ref": "Card 1Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3663342860527336",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "327",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the max range airspeed for autorotation?",
    "answer": "90kts",
    "ref": "Card 1 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8572348994202912",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "328",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the Min ROD airspeed for autorotation?",
    "answer": "60kts",
    "ref": "Card 1 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2650806689634919",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "329",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "State your emergency actions for a double engine failure in flight (hover OGE)",
    "answer": "Enter autorotation (and accelerate if in hover OGE)\u000bSelect Landing Area\u000bWarn Crew/Passengers\u000bMayday Call\u000bHarnesses\u000bFlare, landing attitude, cushion\u000b(Double eng shutdown if time allows)\u000b\u000b[Auto, Talk, SD, Shed bus]",
    "ref": "Card 2",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7366122924722731",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "330",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "State the Double Engine Shutdown drill, in flight?",
    "answer": "Both Eng Main sw...   ...OFF\u000bBoth FADEC sw...   ...OFF\u000b\u000bEngines still running or TOT rising abnormally?\u000bBoth Twist Grips...   ... Turn to shut off",
    "ref": "Card 2",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4689804306253791",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "331",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "State your actions and considerations for TAIL ROTOR DRIVE SHAFT FAILURE - HOGE?\u000b(Nose yaw right).",
    "answer": "...Reduce collective Lever immediately\u000b...Turn both twist grips to a minimum (?)\u000b\u000bIf Height Permits\u000b...Gain Airspeed\u000b... Raise Collective to stop descent and cushion\u000b\u000bAfter Landing\u000b...Perform a double engine emergency shutdown",
    "ref": "Card 2 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2854793886654079",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "332",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "State your actions and considerations for TAIL ROTOR DRIVE SHAFT FAILURE / Fixed Pitch Tail Rotor Control Failure - In forward flight",
    "answer": "...Reduce collective Lever to obtain minimum side slip\u000b...Maintain 70kts airspeed or higher\u000b\u000b...Make a shallow approach keeping the nose left\u000b\u000b...Reduce airspeed close to the ground until nose is aligned with flight direction\u000b...Perform landing\u000b\u000bIf nose direction moves right above 40 kts\u000b...Increase airspeed\u000b...Abort Approach\u000b...Climb and carry out autorotation\u000b...Perform dbl eng emerg shutown",
    "ref": "Card 2 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1134816496632993",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "333",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "State your actions and considerations for a Single Engine Failure in flight?",
    "answer": "...Establish OEI Flight\u000b...Identify affected eng - carry out Single Eng Emerg SD\u000b\u000b...   ...   ...   ... Land As Soon as Practicable",
    "ref": "Card 3 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6257173381745815",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "334",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "State the actions for a SINGLE ENGINE EMERGENCY SHUTDOWN?",
    "answer": "- Ensure OEI\u000b- Switch Bleed Air Off Manually if caption remains\u000b\u000bIdentify Affected Engine with Pilot/Observer\u000b\u000bENG FAIL \u000bENG OIL P\u000bFUEL PRESS\u000bGEN DISCON\u000b\u000bEng Main   ...   ...   ...   ...   IDLE, check indications, OFF",
    "ref": "Card 4 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2008631648495793",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "335",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "T2+",
    "question": "Why should the FADEC of a failed engine not be switched off?",
    "answer": "If the FADEC of affected engine is switched off then FADEC MINR on the remaining engine may appear due to missing redundancy, therefore FADECS should remain on.\u000b\u000bIf there is an indication that the engine is still running or TOT rising abnormally: \u000b\u000bRespective Twist Grip ... Turn to min, verify correct engine then shut off.",
    "ref": "Card 4 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3878294536843896",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "336",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What are the indications of an ENG OVERSPEED - DRIVESHAFT FAILURE?",
    "answer": "Nr   ...   ...   ...   ... Decrease\u000bTQ   ...   ...  ...   ... Zero On Affected Engine\u000bN2   ...   ...   ...  ... Increase above Nr & oscillates if engine   overspeed protection system is active",
    "ref": "Card 5",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8810762646608055",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "337",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What are the immediate actions and landing priority for an Eng Overspeed - DRIVESHAFT FAILURE?",
    "answer": "... Establish OEI flight condition\u000b... Identify Affected Engine and Carry Out Sing Eng Emerg SD\u000b\u000b...   ...   ...   ...   ... Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "Card 5",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8673802274279296",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/06/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "338",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What are the indications of an Engine Overspeed due to Governing Failure?",
    "answer": "ROTOR RPM Warning may come on\u000b\u000bNr and N2 increase and oscillate if overspeed protection is active\u000b\u000bOn affected engine:... Tq, N1 & TOT increase and may oscillate\u000b\u000bOn normal engine: ... Tq, N1 & TOT decrease & may oscillate",
    "ref": "Card 5 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.909497333690524",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "01/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "339",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Engine Overspeed - governor failure?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable\u000b\u000b… Raise Collective to contain Nr & N2 within limits\u000b… Identify Affected engine\u000b… Using TWIST GRIP of affected engine, Reduce Tq until \u000bnormal engine takes up the load\u000b(TWIST GRIP & ENG MAN cautions come on) \u000b… Readjust Collective as req to stay in limits\u000b… Eng Mode Switch of affected engine to MAN\u000b… TWIST GRIP of affected engine Adjust Torque manually \u000bto 20-30% according to weight and ambient conditions\u000b… Adjust Collective without moving twist grip\u000b ... ... … … Land as soon as Practicable\u000bAfter landing … … … Reduce Twist Grip before \u000blowering collective to full down \u000bposition (to keep N2/Nr within \u000blimits)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3455434618517756",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "340",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Engine Oversepeed - driveshaft breakage?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5535988407209516",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "341",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Engine Fire?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible if caption out\u000b\u000bLand Immediately if caption not out",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6638844115659595",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "342",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Low Fuel 1 and/or 2?",
    "answer": "Land within 10 minutes",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.009149407967925",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "343",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for BATT Temp?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8714524344541132",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "344",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for XMSN Oil P?",
    "answer": "Reduce Power\u000bLand As Soon As Possible",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7670769654214382",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "345",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Cabin Fire?",
    "answer": "Attain 65kts VY\u000bLand As Soon Possible",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7995106023736298",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "346",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Elec Fire/Short CCt?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible\u000b(But could be completely Dark Cockpit and no elec - so landing light? etc).",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8831818527542055",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fire,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "347",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority after loss of 2nd AHRS (after reconfiguration of the 1st)?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible? \u000b(Standby instruments presumably)",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7086459430865945",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "afcs,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "348",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the consideration for ENG CHIP?\u000bWhat is the subsequent landing priority?",
    "answer": "If Fuzz Burn is unsuccessful then shut down to idle or off\u000b\u000bLand As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "Card 11 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2052246271632612",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "350",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for a High Eng Oil T?",
    "answer": "(No caution for this)\u000bLand As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5327307628467679",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "351",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for an ENG EXCEED",
    "answer": "Irreversible - Land as soon as Possible\u000bReversible - Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0348075949586927",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "352",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for an FADEC FAIL?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1943299141712486",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "353",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for an Fuel Filt 1 & 2?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible\u000b\u000bLand As Soon As Practicable if just one caption displayed.",
    "ref": "Card 15",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5876521039754152",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,fuel,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "354",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for an ENG CHIP?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Unknown",
    "weight": "0.323302227538079",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "355",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for an XMSN OIL P",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4227321138605475",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "356",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for an XMSN OIL T?",
    "answer": "T & P Normal - Land As Soon As Practicable\u000b\u000bT & P below limits - Land As Soon As Possible",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1305576534941792",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "357",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for a GEN OVHT?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3744978127069771",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "358",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for Abnormal Vibration?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible\u000b\u000bIf reduces below 100 kts - possible ARIS pot - Land As Soon As Practicable.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0717609180137515",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "359",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for a ROTOR BRK?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Possible",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5168433152139187",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "360",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the actions and landing priority for abnormal vibration?",
    "answer": "Indications:\u000bPossible deposit of foreign objects in the control cuffs or ARIS pot failure.\u000b\u000bActions: … … … … Reduce speed\u000b\u000b… … … … LAND AS SOON AS POSSIBLE\u000b\u000bNote: If vibration reduces significantly at speeds below 100kts, it is likely that an ARIS pot has failed. \u000b\u000b… … … … Land as soon as Practicable",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5930496919900179",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "361",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the actions for a HTG OVTEMP?",
    "answer": "(Temp in duct system or cabin exceeded by “a certain amount” & shut off valves are closed automatically)\u000b\u000bActions: … … … … Turn off BLD HTG rheostat \u000b\u000bNote: Heating may be used again, but should be switched off if caution returns.",
    "ref": "Card 22",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0265862811356782",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "362",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the implications of  a CAD FAN or VEMD FAN?",
    "answer": "(Failure of relevant fan has been detected during initial test.)\u000b\u000bDO NOT start engines - maintenance action required.",
    "ref": "Card 22",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0729583417996764",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "363",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the actions for a CPDS OVHT?",
    "answer": "Actions: \u000b… … … … Close “Heating/Defog” knob\u000b… … … … Open “Pull for Air” knob\u000b… … … … Set ventilation blower to max\u000b\u000bIf caption remains ON, land within 30 mins.",
    "ref": "Card 22",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.729580626823008",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "364",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the actions for a CAU DEGRADE?",
    "answer": "(Degraded Caution indication due to loss of CAD lane or both VEMD lanes - on VEMD if CAD is inoperative or on CAD if both VEMD lanes failed) FLI DEGR both sides & ΔN1 not available.\u000b\u000bActions … … … … Press OFF button on CAD\u000b(if CAD has failed) No fuel indications avail.\u000b\u000b… … … … Land as soon as Practicable\u000b\u000bNotes:\u000b1. CAU/FUEL takes priority over ELEC/VEH and appears \u000bautomatically on lower VEMD screen. Use SCROLL \u000bbutton, on VEMD, to toggle between the CAU/FUEL, \u000bSYSTEM STATUS & ELEC/VEH pages. If SCROLL \u000bbutton is inop, press RESET to return to default page.\u000b2. After CAD lane failure, Caution indications on VEMD \u000bscreen are significantly degraded.\u000b3. If High Nr mode selected above 55kts, Nr increases -\u000btherefore select/deselect as required. \u000b4. If CAD & VEMD fail, FLI FAIL on appropriate side",
    "ref": "Card 22",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4512482681311667",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "365",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority for failures of VEMD Lanes/Screens?",
    "answer": "Land As Soon As Practicable",
    "ref": "Card 21 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5504509322345257",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "02/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "366",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The CAD and VEMD are powered by 2 different power supplies each from the essential busbars. How is their operational integrity ensured if one of the busbars should fail?",
    "answer": "The respective power supplies for the CAD and VEMD are connected to both essential busbars.",
    "ref": "00-56",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5715388501994312",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "367",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What parameters are used by the CPDS to distinguish between GROUND and FLIGHT Status?",
    "answer": "Ground\u000bn1 of both engines below <50%\u000bXMSN oil pressure <1 bar\u000b\u000bFlight\u000bN1 on either engine >50%\u000bXMSN oil pressure > 1 bar\u000bCollective level position\u000b>28.5 % TM\u000b>17% PW",
    "ref": "00-56",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.98429155908525",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "368",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "During power up of the CPDS an internal self test is performed, then an external self-test. What is the external self-test and how are faults displayed?",
    "answer": "The external test is a continuity test of the wiring of certain sensors. If a failure is found then a warning for the respective sensor so is displayed with the 'CT' suffix. \u000b\u000beg: ENG CHIP CT",
    "ref": "00-56",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9053589277900757",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "369",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "At power up, how many types of tests are carried out automatically by the CPDS self test sequence, and what are they?",
    "answer": "3\u000b\u000bInternal Self Test\u000bExternal Self Test\u000bIntegrity of peripheral assemblies (INP)",
    "ref": "00-58",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2355438424274325",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "370",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is an INP FAIL indicated to the pilot?",
    "answer": "INP FAIL will appear at the bottom of the MISC column on the CAD. ACK NEEDED prompt is displayed on upper VEMD Screen",
    "ref": "00-58",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4112018737941981",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "371",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How many CPDS Modes are there?",
    "answer": "7 within Flight Status\u000b\u000b3 within Ground Status",
    "ref": "00-62",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7420563320629298",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "372",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the CPDS Modes within the Flight Status?",
    "answer": "CAU/FUEL\u000bFLI\u000bELEC/VEH\u000bSystem Status\u000bIn-flight Power Check\u000bCaution Fuel Fail\u000bCAU Backup",
    "ref": "00-62",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.147502024192363",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "373",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What CPDS Mode is automatically displayed on the CAD?",
    "answer": "CAUTION/FUEL",
    "ref": "00-62",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4821316646412015",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "374",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What CPDS mode is automatically displayed on the upper VEMD page?",
    "answer": "FLI",
    "ref": "00-66",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1830521821975708",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "375",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the Mast Moment Indicator measuring?",
    "answer": "The bending moment of the main motor",
    "ref": "00-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9014493837021292",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "376",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What happens when 50% is reached on the Mast Moment Indicator?",
    "answer": "The yellow range has been entered. A yellow line appears under the letters MM",
    "ref": "00-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3533766749314964",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "377",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What happens when 66% is reached on the Mast Moment Indicator?",
    "answer": "The red range has been entered - the line reverts to red, the LIMIT symbol and the warning GONG come on.",
    "ref": "00-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9668177277781068",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "378",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What administrative action must take place if the red region (>66%) has been entered on the Mast Moment Indicator?",
    "answer": "A logbook entry and maintenance action is required.",
    "ref": "00-70",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2030908190645277",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "379",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Where can messages concerning failures and detected over limits (not visible on the current display) be viewed?",
    "answer": "In the message zone on the FLI mode of VEMD 1 (along the bottom of the FLI)",
    "ref": "00-70",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3186441953293979",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "380",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the hollow triangle at 8.5?",
    "answer": "MAX TOT for starting - appears only during starting",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1058376566506922",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "381",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the yellow band between 9 and 10?",
    "answer": "AEO Take off power range - 5 mins",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0773593601770699",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "382",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the red line at 10?",
    "answer": "AEO Max Take-off power\u000b\u000b78% T2+/P2+",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.7402818175032736",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "383",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the dotted yellow line at 11?",
    "answer": "OEI Max continuous power\u000b\u000b89.5% T2+/P2+",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4955888702534139",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "384",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the red dotted line at 13?",
    "answer": "OEI 2.0 Min Power",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8677148125134408",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "385",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the dotted line at 13.5?",
    "answer": "OEI Transient max 30 secs",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3076107478700578",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "386",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the red circle at 10.4?",
    "answer": "Transient Tq 82% for 10 secs\u000b\u000bUnintended V - VY only.",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6098789996467531",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "387",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is indicated by the yellow 'T' in the inverted yellow triangle?",
    "answer": "Training Mode is activated",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6239379281178117",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "388",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the small red triangle at 13.5?",
    "answer": "Topping symbol indicates the selected OEI 2.0 min or 30 sec power limitation.",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7265775566920638",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "389",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What limit is indicated by the red triangle at 11?",
    "answer": "TOT for starting transient - appears only during starting\u000b\u000bTM Max 5 secs\u000bPW Max 2 secs",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6182338986545801",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "390",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the actions for a FIRE in flight?",
    "answer": "IN FLIGHT\u000b… Establish OEI flight condition\u000b… Respective EMER sw … Open sw guard, press & release\u000b\u000bNote: Respective engine will automatically cut off, EMER\u000bOFF SW panel shows “Active” & F VALVE CL illuminates on CAD (and FIRE EXT, if bottle has fired below 50% N1)\u000b\u000b… Identify Affected Engine and carry out Single Engine \u000bEmergency Shutdown SEE CARD 4 REV\u000b\u000bIf FIRE WARNING light goes OFF:\u000b… … … … LAND AS SOON AS POSSIBLE\u000bIf FIRE WARNING light remains ON:\u000b… … … … LAND IMMEDIATELY",
    "ref": "Card 6",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0101516218855977",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,fire,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "391",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the actions for a BATT TEMP in flight?",
    "answer": "In Flight\u000bBat Master … … … OFF \u000b… ... … … LAND AS SOON AS POSSIBLE\u000b\u000bEngines … … … … Shut down & perform Visual \u000bInspection of Battery\u000b\u000bIf Visual Inspection reveals NO battery overheating\u000b\u000bStart –up … … … … Perform\u000bBattery Master … … … Off\u000bNote: Continue flight in VMC only. BAT DISCON on CAD\u000b\u000b… … … … Land as soon as Practicable",
    "ref": "Card 6 Rev",
    "source": "FRCs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2942240084521472",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,frc,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "392",
    "topic": "Emergency Actions",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the landing priority and immediate actions for XMSN Chip caption?",
    "answer": "… Check XMSN Pressure in normal range\u000b\u000b… … … … Land as soon as Practicable\u000b\u000bNote: Reduce Power as much as possible",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4110902445390821",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/07/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "393",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Do NVG permit any reductions in limitations, minima or requirements?",
    "answer": "No - they enhance visual capability but there are no permitted reductions in:\u000b\u000b• Weather minima\u000b• Minimum separation distances and operating heights\u000b• Landing site size or type\u000b• Aircraft performance limitations\u000b• FTL requirements.",
    "ref": "8.11.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4155258862301707",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "394",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What ground equipment should be available at an NVIS Operating base?",
    "answer": "• A source of local cloud base and visibility information\u000b• A light level prediction tool\u000b• An NVG checking system such as a Hoffmann 20/20 test set",
    "ref": "8.11.3.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2712325383909046",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "395",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What documentation does the aircraft require for NVIS flight and how should this requirement be maintained?",
    "answer": "Each helicopter and all associated NVIS equipment shall have been issued with an appropriate airworthiness approval in complete accordance with the relevant regulations. \u000b\u000bAny subsequent modification or maintenance to the aircraft shall be in compliance with the NVIS airworthiness approval if the aircraft is to be used for NVIS operations",
    "ref": "8.11.3.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4951122812926768",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "396",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name some risks areas associated with NVIS Operations?",
    "answer": "• Weather conditions, and availability and accuracy of weather information\u000b• Terrain and obstacles\u000b• Illumination levels & cultural light levels in the operational area\u000b• Crew recency & overall experience with NVG operations\u000b• Crew disorientation and/or loss of situational awareness\u000b• Crew vision, health and fatigue issues (with emphasis on NVIS-specific issues)\u000b• Human factors issues (e.g. complacency and overconfidence)\u000b• Engineering Issues, e.g. lighting, and windscreen and window condition\u000b• Increased likelihood of advertent entry into IMC",
    "ref": "8.11.4.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8261060500517486",
    "notes": "Physical, physio, environment, terrain",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "397",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Name some risk mitigation for NVIS Operations?",
    "answer": "• Extensive crew selection, training, recency and coordination procedures including crew SOPs, (See\u000bOM-D for training procedures)\u000b• Full pre-flight briefing and equipment checking facilities at the operating base\u000b• Procedures for the checking of aircraft and crew equipment for NVIS operations\u000b• Specific NVIS Flight Procedures & Crew Responsibilities\u000b• Post flight debriefing and analysis\u000b• Fatigue Management Measures",
    "ref": "8.11.4.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5349700250662863",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "398",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 2 general conditions/limitations apply to NVIS operations?",
    "answer": "Over water flights out of sight of land are prohibited\u000b\u000bReversion to normal night flying techniques must be available at all times",
    "ref": "8.11.9.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4124338161200285",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "399",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "The combined visible and near-IR spectrum of NVG is 665 - 930mm. What relevance does this have to obstruction lights?",
    "answer": "Some red LED obstruction lights are not visible to NVG as they emit in the range of 610nm to 700nm",
    "ref": "8.11.9.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3718235320411623",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "400",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 3 mitigation techniques should be employed against red LED obstruction lights?",
    "answer": "Crews should periodically scan under the goggles (when at low altitudes)\u000b\u000bNVIS CRew members should call-out LED obstacles\u000b\u000bA landing should be aborted and/or a climb to higher altitude initiated if an obstacle is not clear to the pilot.",
    "ref": "8.11.9.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0835069990716874",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "401",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What should the crew composition be for NVG ops?",
    "answer": "The absolute minimum crew for an NVIS flight shall be one NVIS pilot and one NVIS TFO, suitably qualified and current. \u000b\u000bWhere an ad hoc landing is required, the crew ideally should consist of crew of one NVIS pilot and 2\u000bNVIS TFOs, although one of the TFOs may be non-NVIS qualified. \u000b\u000bIn exceptional circumstances the Commander\u000bcan fly single pilot if required to complete a critical task.",
    "ref": "8.11.9.3",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7105550728738308",
    "notes": "Different scenarios imply different rquments",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "402",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "According to the OMA, what 3 items must be serviceable for NVIS ops, prior to flight?",
    "answer": "• Radar Altimeter fully operative including AVAD functions\u000b• Thermal Camera System\u000b• Search and Landing Light (steerable landing lamp)",
    "ref": "8.11.9.4.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7431140197440982",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "403",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What briefing must the pilot carry out prior to NVIS Operations?",
    "answer": "The NVIS Pre-Flight Briefing as listed in the OMA 8.11.9.4.3",
    "ref": "8.11.9.4.3",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3397940811701119",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "404",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What should the pilot respond if they hear a TFO call \"Go around, Go around\"?",
    "answer": "The pilots response (and actions) should be \"Going Around - Going Around\"",
    "ref": "8.11.9.5.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.372291091363877",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "405",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What should the pilot state prior to deliberately flying through a rad alt warning for the purposes of approach/landing?",
    "answer": "“Continuing to Descend” or “Continuing\u000bto Land”",
    "ref": "8.11.9.5.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0227524079382419",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "406",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What height should the rad alt bug be set for take-off?",
    "answer": "500' and 120' set on ND DH",
    "ref": "8.11.9.5.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1574340686202049",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "407",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What should the ND DH bug be set to for the duration of an NVG flight?",
    "answer": "120'",
    "ref": "8.11.9.5.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1601012363098561",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "408",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When can the rad alt bug be set to 250'?",
    "answer": "During an HLS low recce\u000b\u000bOn Final approach when the touch down point has been identified",
    "ref": "8.11.9.5.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9969307091087104",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "409",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "At what height, and what conditions should apply, for transition from/to NVG/Reversionary flight",
    "answer": "Safe flight configuration\u000b>500' MSD\u000bClear of obstacles\u000b\u000bAP holds may be used",
    "ref": "8.11.9.6.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1200905200093984",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "410",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What actions should the pilot take if he/she experiences a goggle failure prior to TDP?",
    "answer": "Land (Look under NVG & use landing lamp) or Continue to Safe flight",
    "ref": "8.11.9.7.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6652844240888953",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "411",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What actions should the pilot take if he/she experiences a goggle failure after TDP?",
    "answer": "Climb above 500’ MSD and achieve a safe flight configuration",
    "ref": "8.11.9.7.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7853486849926413",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "412",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What actions should the pilot take if he/she experiences a goggle failure after LDP?",
    "answer": "Land (Look under NVG & use landing lamp)",
    "ref": "8.11.9.7.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3732413286343217",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "413",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What actions should the pilot take if he/she experiences a goggle failure before LDP?",
    "answer": "Go around to Safe Transit Height",
    "ref": "8.11.9.7.1",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2735863239504397",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "414",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "If NVG are in use at the time of an emergency then what positions should the NVG be in during the emergency handling?",
    "answer": "Down and in use for immediate actions and, if required, an immediate landing. \u000b\u000bThen subsequent actions, at >500',  carried out with goggles up. \u000b\u000bSubsequent landing and other actions can be carried out with goggles back down if required.",
    "ref": "8.11.9.7.2",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0967139736749231",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "415",
    "topic": "NVG Ops",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What additional actions apply to the inadvertent IMC procedure when on NVG?",
    "answer": "• The Commander achieves safe climb condition looking under the NVG\u000b\u000b• Raise NVG\u000b\u000b• Continue using IF techniques and AP functions and recover to an airfield using standard inadvertent\u000bIMC techniques.",
    "ref": "8.11.9.7.3",
    "source": "OMA",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1922239726409316",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "416",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the definition of 'Continued T/O Distance or Takeoff Distance required'?",
    "answer": "Horizontal distance along takeoff path from the start of takeoff to the point at which the helicopter attains and remains at least 35 feet above takeoff surface, attains and remains VTOSS and establishes a positive\u000brate of climb...",
    "ref": "Page 8",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.224238053895533",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "417",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the definition of a hostile area?",
    "answer": "(A) A safe forced landing cannot be accomplished, because the surface is inadequate.\u000b(B) The helicopter occupants cannot be adequately protected from the elements.\u000b(C) no consistent SAR cover.\u000b(D) unacceptable risk of endangering persons or property on ground.",
    "ref": "Page 8",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3033970915712416",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "418",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the definition of a Heliport?",
    "answer": "Aerodrome, defined area of land, water or a structure intended to be used wholly or in part for arrival, departure and surface movement of helicopters.",
    "ref": "Page 8",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1702863820828497",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "419",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the dimensions of a 'Restricted Heliport''?",
    "answer": "Restricted Heliport\u000b\u000bDimensions min. 15 m x 15 m",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.995466582942754",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "420",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the dimensions of a 'Surface Level Heliport''?",
    "answer": "A heliport located on the ground or on the water, having dimensions of at least 15 m x 15 m (under day and night conditions). \u000b\u000bThe surface shall be solid to generate ground effect.",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5454066121019423",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "421",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is Takeoff Segment 1",
    "answer": "Horizontal distance from end of continued takeoff distance to climb to 200 feet AGL with VTOSS.",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0304929548874497",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "422",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define TDP?",
    "answer": "Takeoff decision point: The point used in determining takeoff path performance from which a power unit failure having been recognized at this point, either a rejected takeoff may be made or a takeoff safely\u000bcontinued.\u000b\u000bJAR OPS Terminology",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6177299367263913",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "423",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define LDP?",
    "answer": "Landing decision point: The point used in determining landing performance from which a power unit failure having been recognized.\u000b\u000bAt this point the landing may be safely continued or a balked landing initiated.\u000b\u000bJAR OPS Terminology",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8180113034322859",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "424",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define VTOSS?",
    "answer": "Takeoff safety speed: Airspeed to assure rate of climb of 100 ft/min with 2.5 min power with helicopter gross mass specified for ambient conditions.",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.409744915086776",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "425",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define VY?",
    "answer": "Best rate of climb speed: Airspeed which leads to the highest gain in altitude in a specified period of time.",
    "ref": "Page 9",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7757063941098749",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "426",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When using the CAT A calculation graphs, how much of the wind component can the pilot factor into calculations?",
    "answer": "Unless otherwise authorized by operating\u000bregulations, the pilot is not authorized to credit\u000bmore than 50% of the performance increase\u000bresulting from the actual headwind component.",
    "ref": "Page 47",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9723891266621648",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "427",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Unless the weather is very hot or the altitude is high, what usually are the respective figures for Continued Take-Off Distance Required and Rejected Take-off Distance Required?",
    "answer": "Continued Take-Off Distance Required = 210M\u000b\u000bRejected Take-off Distance Required = 250M\u000b\u000b(answers taken from graphs)",
    "ref": "Page 44",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2718120100907981",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "428",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What may influence the climb performance in the OEI Climb phase?",
    "answer": "Significant turns",
    "ref": "Page 16",
    "source": "EC135 Training Manual Cat A",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.720981382764876",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "429",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is indicated in the 'high information zone' and where is it?",
    "answer": "It is in the respective top left/right hand corner of the FLI and can indicate the following:\u000b\u000bENG FAIL\u000bFADEC FAIL\u000bENG MANU\u000bIDLE\u000bTRAIN\u000bTRAIN IDLE",
    "ref": "00-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6964987530373037",
    "notes": "6 items",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "430",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is indicated in the 'low information zone' and where is it?",
    "answer": "It is in the respective bottom left/right hand corner of the FLI and can indicate the following:\u000b\u000bFLI FAIL\u000bFLI DEGR",
    "ref": "00-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7199926413595676",
    "notes": "6 items",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "431",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What three indications (for each engine) are indicated in the FLI/Parameter Zone?",
    "answer": "TRQ\u000b\u000bTOT\u000b\u000bN1",
    "ref": "00-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9722733707167208",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "432",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Describe how the onset of limits is indicated on the FLI?",
    "answer": "The limiting parameter is indicated by the white rectangle. It's underlined in yellow if a caution if in a caution range. The underlining changes to flashing red if a limit is reached.",
    "ref": "00-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7636705208569765",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "433",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How is a failed parameter indicated in the FLI?",
    "answer": "If a parameter fails then it is displayed in Yellow without its numerical value.",
    "ref": "00-72",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1380718685686588",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "434",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "Under what conditions will the ENG EXCEED caution appear on the ground and what action must be taken?",
    "answer": "Exceedance of a time excursion in 2min or 30 sec power band\u000b\u000bSignificant exceedance of 30sec, ie, reaching and maintaining the following values for 5 secs: \u000b\u000b136% Tq\u000b104.8% Delta N1\u000b1024 deg TOT\u000b\u000bThe ENG EXCEED caution is stored in the FADEC and appears at next engine startup",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6377627132460475",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "435",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "Under what conditions will the ENG EXCEED caution appear on the ground and what action must be taken?",
    "answer": "Exceedance of a time excursion in 2min or 30 sec power band\u000b\u000bSignificant exceedance of 30sec, ie, reaching and maintaining the following values for 5 secs: \u000b\u000b133% Tq\u000b104.3% Delta N1\u000b990 deg TOT\u000b(only possible in event of topping failure)\u000b\u000bThe ENG EXCEED caution is stored in the FADEC and appears at next engine startup",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.125543070025742",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "436",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 2 circumstances will activate the LIMIT warning and audio warning GONG?",
    "answer": "OEI / AEO time limit exceedance\u000b\u000bLimiting value exceedance",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9344654246233404",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "437",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What activity must take place if a red limit is exceeded?",
    "answer": "Logbook entry and maintenance action is required. Depending on time and maximum value the lifetime of the components can be reduced or totally expired.",
    "ref": "00-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.906272690743208",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "13/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "438",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Including optional extras not fitted to Police aircraft, what parameters can be displayed on the Electrical and Vehicle parameters page (lower VEMD)?",
    "answer": "OAT\u000bIce rate / Cargo Hook / Cable length\u000bVoltage and current\u000bOil Pressure and temperatures (eng 1, 2 / XMSN)",
    "ref": "00-78",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0642606471665203",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "14/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical"
  },
  {
    "id": "439",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Describe how the Elec and Vehicle Parameters mode displays temperatures/pressures when they approach/reach their limits?",
    "answer": "The numerical value for a parameter will be underlined in yellow when it reaches its caution range. When the limit is reached the underline changes to flashing red and the limit bar graph will widen.\u000b\u000bThere is no audio warning associated.",
    "ref": "00-78",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0001664725132286",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "14/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "440",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Describe what the in flight power check achieves and how?",
    "answer": "During the check the FADEC will calculate a maximum permissible value (TOT for PW, N1 for TM) based on the environmental conditions.\u000b\u000bThis is then compared to the determined power*.\u000b\u000bIf the calculated value is above the determined value then the power margin is positive. \u000b\u000bIf the engine is no longer capable of producing sufficient power then the power margin is underlined yellow and is negative.\u000b\u000b*Presumably this is a factory pre-determined, theoretical power.",
    "ref": "00-88",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4758287165313959",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "14/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "441",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What 5 parameters are required for the EPC (in flight power check)?",
    "answer": "TRQ\u000bTOT\u000bN1\u000bPO\u000bTO\u000b\u000bPO = Ambient pressure\u000bTO = Ambient temperature",
    "ref": "00-90",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.760377906728536",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "14/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "442",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is indicated by the image shown?",
    "answer": "This is an invalid EPC result due to any of 5 parameters not being available - in this case the unavailable parameters are N1 and ambient pressure.\u000b\u000bThe required parameters are:\u000b\u000bTRQ\u000bTOT\u000bN1\u000bPO\u000bTO",
    "ref": "00-92",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.4298627818934619",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "14/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "443",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the collective term for the module circled in the picture and, broadly speaking, what does it do?",
    "answer": "Fuel Management Module\u000b\u000bThe FMM works in conjunction with the EEC to control metered fuel flow over the entire operational range of the engine.",
    "ref": "06-68",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.2060251552611589",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "444",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture and what is its purpose?",
    "answer": "Fuel Management Module torque motor - in automatic mode, this is controlled by the EEC and the torque motor rotates the fuel metering valve.",
    "ref": "06-68",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.8885050457902253",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "445",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture?",
    "answer": "Fuel Filter",
    "ref": "06-68",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.5547460890375078",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "446",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture?",
    "answer": "Fuel Filter Impending Bypass Switch",
    "ref": "06-68",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.5128695801831782",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "447",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture?",
    "answer": "PMA (alternator) - provides AC to  FADEC",
    "ref": "06-84",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.6419184636324644",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "448",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture?",
    "answer": "Fire detector",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.2447260525077581",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "449",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture?",
    "answer": "Emergency Engine control",
    "ref": "06-112",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.5402640029788017",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "450",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture and what is its purpose?",
    "answer": "Data Collection Unit (DCU)\u000b\u000bIt collects data on accumulated cycles of each rotating component and the info can be downloaded using PC communication. \u000b\u000bOn the TurboMecca engine, a Torque confirmation box does some equivalent tasks (ie reference values which are unique to the output shaft for torque measuring purposes.",
    "ref": "06-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.6429424840025604",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "451",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What item is circled in the picture and what is its purpose?",
    "answer": "Thermally controlled engine oil cooler valve - this prevents cold oil entering the oil cooling system until a suitable temperature is reached such that viscosity of oil is suitable for passage through the cooling system.",
    "ref": "06-76",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.0247134226374328",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "15/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "452",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Under what circumstances will the display shown in the picture be visible and on what screen?",
    "answer": "The CAUTION/BACKUP page is displayed on the CAD only if the VEMD fails completely or has been deactivated.",
    "ref": "00-94",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.5970614342950284",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "453",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Under what circumstances will the display shown in the picture be visible and on what screen?",
    "answer": "The CAUTION/FUEL Fail page is displayed automatically on the lower VEMD screen if the CAD has failed.",
    "ref": "00-96",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.0168251669965684",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "needs_image",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "454",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When the CAUTION/BACKUP page is displayed on the CAD, what information is available?",
    "answer": "- Cautions (degraded indication only)\u000b- Advisories\u000b- Numeric readout of fuel contents in main / supply tanks\u000b- Eng 1 and 2 Tq on analogue scale with numeric limiting values\u000b\u000bIf a Tq channel fails the associated pointer and numerical readout are faded out; the scale and Tq turn yellow. \u000b\u000bNo other pages or data can be presented",
    "ref": "00-94",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0097233038395643",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "455",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "T2",
    "question": "If the CAD fails, the lower VEMD will switch to the CAUTION/FUEL FAIL page. What other indication is lost and what warning will be triggered?",
    "answer": "Delta N1 information in the FLI is lost and the FLI DEGR caution is triggered.",
    "ref": "00-92",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.1875755782239139",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "Yes",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "456",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the CAU DEGR caution indicate in this scenario?",
    "answer": "It indicates that only a degraded caution list is available?",
    "ref": "00-92",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Picture",
    "weight": "0.0481407572515308",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "21/07/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "457",
    "topic": "Limitations",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "How should cockpit ventilation be configured when OAT > 30 deg?",
    "answer": "Pull for heating/defog pushed down\u000bPull for air lever pulled up",
    "ref": "2 - 7",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5461166757158935",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "458",
    "topic": "Lifting System",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "When can lead lag resonance occur and how is it mitigated?",
    "answer": "May occur in 60-68% rotor RPM range. When RPM is in this range cyclic should be neutral and collective fully down to prevent potentially severe damage due to stimulation of this lead-lag resonance.",
    "ref": "2 - 8",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0368494377471506",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "459",
    "topic": "Electrical",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the maximum current flow when using the 28 v DC gpu?",
    "answer": "700amp",
    "ref": "2 - 11",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9972855243831874",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "05/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical"
  },
  {
    "id": "460",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "Below which temperature is fuel anti-icing additives required?",
    "answer": "Below -30deg",
    "ref": "2 - 14",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3259147116914391",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "461",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What is the total unusable fuel in the aircraft?",
    "answer": "7.6 kg",
    "ref": "2 - 14",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1902897977270185",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel"
  },
  {
    "id": "462",
    "topic": "General",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "What are the total il quantities for:\u000bEach eng tank?\u000bMain transmission?\u000bFenestron gearbox?",
    "answer": "Eng: 4.5L\u000bM Tx: 10 - 12L\u000bFenestron: 0.5L",
    "ref": "2 - 15",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5758079388178885",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "463",
    "topic": "Flight Control",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "Explain the purpose and features of the collective override stop?",
    "answer": "The coll pitch travel is limited by an override stop\u000b\u000bIn the event of an emergency, if inc pitch is required, the stop can be exceeded. The required override control force is approx 5.6 lbs (25 newton)",
    "ref": "2 - 17",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0278935586102306",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "464",
    "topic": "Electrical",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "On the ground, when can a CB be reset?",
    "answer": "Only after maintenance has determined the cause of the trip and has determined that it's safe to reset.",
    "ref": "3 - 2",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5584343774244189",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical"
  },
  {
    "id": "465",
    "topic": "Electrical",
    "variant": "P2+",
    "question": "In flight when can a CB be reset?",
    "answer": "Shall not be reset unless doing so is consistent with specified procedures or, in the judgement of the PIC resetting the CB is necessary for safe completion of the flight.",
    "ref": "3 - 3",
    "source": "P2+ FLM",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5019269813783467",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "29/12/2021",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,fadec"
  },
  {
    "id": "466",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the consequence for a take-off if an engine fails after TDP?",
    "answer": "The take-off must be continued",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8379359855316579",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "467",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the consequence for a take-off if an engine fails prior to TDP?",
    "answer": "The take-off must be rejected.",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6378553565591574",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "468",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the consequence for an approach if an engine fails prior to LDP?",
    "answer": "The approach may be continued or elect to go around",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6182467499747872",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "469",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What is the consequence for an approach if an engine fails after LDP?",
    "answer": "The landing must be continued.",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0990218394435942",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "470",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the topping button select and where is the button?",
    "answer": "It's on the collective - it switches between 30 sec and 2 minute power limitations.",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.331570124719292",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "471",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What does the topping button default to after an engine failure?",
    "answer": "30 seconds",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2429918837733566",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "472",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "How much headwind component can pilots credit when using CAT A performance charts?",
    "answer": "50% or reported headwind",
    "ref": "4.2.2.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8720631026662886",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "473",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What environmental factors guarantee (or not) that the aircraft can be operated at max gross mass of 2910kg for Clear Heliport profiles?",
    "answer": "If at the surface of the heliport the OAT is less than 30 deg and the pressure altitude is less than 3000'",
    "ref": "4.2.3",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2995100584812462",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "474",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What defines an elevated heliport?",
    "answer": "A heliport which is at least 3 metres above the surrounding surface",
    "ref": "4.2.4",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8154229754582046",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "475",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the dimensions and requirements for a surface level heliport?",
    "answer": "Dimensions must be at least 15m x 15m\u000b\u000bNot aove 3m in height\u000b\u000bSurface must be able to generate ground effect\u000b\u000bObstacle free area 30m in width overlaying the TLOF\u000b(touch down and lift off area)",
    "ref": "4.2.4",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5028177043423057",
    "notes": "3 sets of dimension and a surface",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "476",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What environmental factors guarantee (or not) that the aircraft can be operated at max gross mass of 2910kg for VTOL 1 or 2 profile?",
    "answer": "If at the surface of the heliport the OAT is less than +17 deg and the pressure altitude is zero feet. This reduces to approx 2840kg at 2000' PA for the same temperature",
    "ref": "4.2.3",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4698892747983336",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "477",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "In still wind conditions what is the vertical and horizontal position of VTOL 1 TDP expressed in feet and metres respectively?",
    "answer": "TDP is 120' AHE and approximately 80 metres behind the helipad.",
    "ref": "4.2.4",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.979876772966236",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "478",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define LDP parameters for a VTOL 1 (height, speed, ROD)?",
    "answer": "30kt IAS, 120' AHE and approx 400'/min ROD",
    "ref": "4.2.4",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.186778225004673",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "479",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What are the dimensions for a heliport suitable for VTOL 3?",
    "answer": "75m x 15m\u000b\u000bObstacle free area of at least 30 m in width overlaying the TLOF to conform to FATO requirements",
    "ref": "4.2.8",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3055210011079907",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "480",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define the vertical and horizontal position of TDP for a VTOL 3 in still wind conditions?",
    "answer": "240' AHE, approx 60m behind the take-off point with an IP at 120' vertically above the take-off point.",
    "ref": "4.2.8",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0894892537035048",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/01/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "482",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What frequency band does the localiser operate in?",
    "answer": "108 - 111.95 MHz",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9488621773198248",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "483",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How are localiser frequencies distinguished from VOR?",
    "answer": "The localiser uses odd 100kHz frequencies and the odd frequencies plus 50 kHz.\u000b\u000beg: \u000b108.1  \u000b108.15\u000b108.3",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4932705722749232",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "484",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What frequency band does the glidepath use?",
    "answer": "40 spot UHF frequencies from 329.3 - 335 MHz paired with the VHF channels",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9159638960845768",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "485",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How is the ILS glidepath frequency selected?",
    "answer": "It is automatically selected when the paired VHF channel is dialled up/tuned.",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0243025058880448",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "486",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What frequency do the marker beacons operate on?",
    "answer": "All marker beacons operate on 75 MHz",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4778738715685904",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "487",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the ident radio wave?",
    "answer": "It's a 1020 Hz tone AM on the localiser carrier wave",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7074771565385163",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "488",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "If an ILS frequency IDENT is likely to be confused, then what additional letter is used?",
    "answer": "It's preceded by the letter I to emphasise it's an ILS",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2364023812115192",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "489",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "On what categories of ILS can voice be superimposed on the localiser carrier?",
    "answer": "On some Category I or II systems",
    "ref": "6.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5279148211702704",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "490",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is displayed to indicate unreliable localiser of glideslope signals?",
    "answer": "Red flags on the instrument indicate unreliable localiser or glideslope signals.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.323180753737688",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "491",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Which display is most sensitive - localiser or glidepath?",
    "answer": "The localiser display is less sensitive than the glidepath. \u000b\u000bAnswer: Glidepath",
    "ref": "6.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2773777693510055",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "492",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the modulation of the localiser beams?",
    "answer": "The localiser consists of 2 overlapping beams, one AM modulated at 90Hz and other AM modulated at 150 Hz",
    "ref": "6.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6733668306842446",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "493",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What colour convention is used for the localiser beams?",
    "answer": "The 90 Hz signal is known as the yellow lobe and the 150 hz is the blue lobe.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6234136787243187",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "494",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Where is the localiser transmitter usually located?",
    "answer": "Usually in line with the runway centreline, 300m off the upwind end. The frangible aerial maybe 20 metres wide and 3 metres high.",
    "ref": "6.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7855501440353692",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "495",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the typical size of the localiser transmitter?",
    "answer": "The frangible aerial maybe 20 metres wide and 3 metres high and consists of a number of dipole and reflector elements.",
    "ref": "6.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6163139827549458",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "496",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Out to what range and height are the localiser signals protected?",
    "answer": "25 NM to a height of just over 6000'",
    "ref": "6.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8295277142897248",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "497",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the coverage, in degrees, either side of the centreline for a Cat 1 ILS?",
    "answer": "10 deg either side at the limits of the protected range and 35 deg either side when within 17 NM of the transmitter.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1694428427144885",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "498",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the risk of using the localiser outside of the protected range?",
    "answer": "Reverse sense indications may occur",
    "ref": "6.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3159424955956638",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "499",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is an offset localiser?",
    "answer": "If the transmitter cannot be placed on the centreline then it is placed next to the runway  and the bean is adjusted to pass through the runway centreline at Decision Height",
    "ref": "6.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.910692852921784",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "500",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the consequence for the procedure if the offset is more than 5 degrees?",
    "answer": "It no longer qualifies as a Precision Approach and must be flown to an MDH/MDA",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1775040007196366",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "501",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the modulation of the glidepath signals?",
    "answer": "Two lobes are AM modulated at 90 and 150 Hz respectively The top lobe is 90Hz and gives 'fly down' indications. The bottom lobe is 150 and gives 'fly up' indications. The top lobe is 'yellow' and the bottom is 'blue'.",
    "ref": "6.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1097884913906455",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "502",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "According to ICAO Annexe 10, what is the notional glidepath?",
    "answer": "3 degrees",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.07775459298864",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "503",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Where is the glidepath aerial positioned?",
    "answer": "Next to the instrument touch down point, about 300m from the threshold and approximately 120 m off the runway centreline.",
    "ref": "6.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3140283883549273",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "504",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How many degrees displacement is full scale for the localiser?",
    "answer": "2.5 degrees",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5184877589344977",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "505",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How many degrees displacement is full scale for the glidepath?",
    "answer": "0.7 degrees",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3011828297749161",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "506",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Viewed from the side, what is the base and upper limit of the glidepath angle?",
    "answer": "Base: 0.45 x the GP Angle\u000bUpper: 1.75 x GP angle",
    "ref": "6.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7659933711402118",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "507",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Viewed from above, what is the range and azimuth of the ILS glidepath?",
    "answer": "10nm and 8 deg either side of the centreline.",
    "ref": "6.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.397723483853042",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "508",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Above what (published) glide angle is the approach considered to be a steep approach?",
    "answer": "3.5 degrees and the coverage only extends to 8 NM",
    "ref": "6.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2491044453345239",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "509",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What causes false glideslopes?",
    "answer": "Transmission side lobes.",
    "ref": "6.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5881032194010913",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "510",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What safeguards against a false glideslope?",
    "answer": "You will never encounter a false glideslope if you approach the glidepath from below.",
    "ref": "6.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2413171087391674",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "511",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "At what angle is the first false glidepath likely to be encountered?",
    "answer": "Around 6 degrees",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0115824150852859",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "512",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How is the procedure designed to avoid false glideslopes?",
    "answer": "A standard ILS procedure begins with level flight somewhere between 1500' and 2500'at some range from the aerodrome and the aircraft is steered to become established on the localiser.",
    "ref": "6.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2320775743573904",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "513",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the marker beacons?",
    "answer": "It's an ICAO requirement (Doc 8168) that the final approach area contains a fix or facility that allows the pilot to cross-check height against range. The marker beacons provide for this requirement.",
    "ref": "6.6",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9961081128567456",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "514",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "At what ranges are the marker beacons?",
    "answer": "Approx\u000b\u000bInner Marker: threshold\u000bMiddle marker: 0.6 NM\u000bOuter Marker: 4 NM",
    "ref": "6.6",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8751810262911021",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "515",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Markers might also be known as?",
    "answer": "Z Markers",
    "ref": "6.6",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3286121576093137",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "516",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are the respective colours and audio pitch of the respective markers?",
    "answer": "Outer: Blue, 400 Hz, \"---\"\u000bMiddle: Amber, 1300 Hz, \"-.-\"\u000bInner: White, 3000 Hz, \"..\" (morse)",
    "ref": "6.6",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2929254570044576",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "517",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How is the DME usually selected?",
    "answer": "It's usually paired with the ILS and therefore automatically selected when the ILS is tuned.",
    "ref": "6.6",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7186376601457596",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "518",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'high' setting on the marker indication panel?",
    "answer": "When airways markers are used the 'High' setting is used for 'High Altitude'.",
    "ref": "6.6",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5904152900911868",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "519",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What limits of deflection should the pilot maintain (remain within) when established?",
    "answer": "The pilot has to stay within half-scale deflection of the required track.",
    "ref": "6.7",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0825122082605957",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "520",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What should the pilot do if the aircraft deviates outside half-scale?",
    "answer": "An immediate missed approach should be carried out.",
    "ref": "6.7",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1767792515456676",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "521",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Where in the world are back-course procedures permitted and not permitted?",
    "answer": "They are relatively common in the US and Canada. They are not approved in Europe.",
    "ref": "6.7",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1142946896143257",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "522",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What indications do back course procedures show?",
    "answer": "When tracking away, they indicate in the correct sense. When tracking towards a back course, they operate in the opposite sense.",
    "ref": "6.7",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3457459174096584",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "523",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "For a back-course procedure (where permitted), how could the correct sense be displayed on the ILS scales?",
    "answer": "Rotate the HSI 180 deg (QDM), if possible with the type of equipment.",
    "ref": "6.7",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4411174058914184",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "524",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the respective ILS categories, DH and RVR?",
    "answer": "I  200, RVR 550m\u000bII 100, RVR 300m\u000bIIIA 0, RVR 200m\u000bIIIB 0, RVR 75m\u000bIIIC 0, RVR 0m\u000b\u000bCat IIIC has never been in commercial use",
    "ref": "6.8",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5089071812108159",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "525",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the difference between the ILS 'critical' and 'sensitive' areas on an airfield?",
    "answer": "Vehicles and aircraft are excluded from the critical area when it's in use\u000b\u000bIn the sensitive area, vehicles and aircraft are controlled.",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9941486390307545",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "526",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What effect can disturbance of the critical area cause?",
    "answer": "It may cause scalloping - rapid indicator changes from side-to-side of the intended approach path which cannot be followed by the aircraft.",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3854984394274652",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "527",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name 5 things that can disturb ILS signals?",
    "answer": "Transmitter faults\u000bAntenna damage\u000bInterfering signals - eg VHF FM Radio \u000bEnvironmental disturbances\u000bMulti-effect paths",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3602775502949952",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "528",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What happens to the ident if the signal strength is reduced?",
    "answer": "The ident signal is removed with 6 seconds for a Cat I system and 2 seconds for a Cat II or III system",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8384663839824498",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "529",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How are the localiser and glidepath signals monitored?",
    "answer": "Via integral monitors in the antennae and both near and far field RF monitors.",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.962077929638326",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "530",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How do the warning flags of the ILS receiver equipment operate?",
    "answer": "When the receiving signal is lost or weakens, electromagnets (which are normally held out of view by the current of the modulating signal), are released into view on the instrument.",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6107115638442338",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "531",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Why might FM radio stations be an issue for ILS receivers?",
    "answer": "Because they can operate at signals close to the ILS at 108 MHz.",
    "ref": "6.9",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8553540962748228",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "532",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is ILS receiving equipment fitted with to prevent FM radio interference?",
    "answer": "FM immune filters",
    "ref": "6.10",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.71738469786942",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "533",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "In terms of systems and tech, in older aircraft, what might 'VFR only' imply on a placard on the VHF NAV receiver?",
    "answer": "It means the onboard ILS equipment is not fitted with FM immune filters.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6570394905284047",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "534",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "On an ILS approach plate, what does the letter 'D' mean in front of the published ILS frequency?",
    "answer": "It means the ILS has a built-in DME facility.",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "Captain Joe YouTube",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9436447606422008",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "535",
    "topic": "Radio Nav",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What ICAO annexe do all ILS procedures and equipment to comply with?",
    "answer": "Annexe 10",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0757358549162745",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "536",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What document stipulates a requirement for integrity monitoring?",
    "answer": "ICAO Annexe 10",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0996016133576631",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "537",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What were the names of the systems that used to improve the accuracy of GPS?",
    "answer": "Differential GPS- it aimed to improve accuracy down to 1 metre",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.384812710341066",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "538",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "There are systems in place that aim to monitor and improve GPS. What 3 categories do these fall into?",
    "answer": "Airborne Based Augmentation Systems (ABAS)\u000bGround based augmentation (GBAS)\u000bSatellite Based Augmentation Systems (SBAS)\u000b\u000bGBAS and SBAS can provide increase in accuracy - differential GPS",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.2098778113722801",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "539",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What 2 types of ABAS are there?",
    "answer": "RAIM - receiver autonomous integrity monitoring\u000bAAIM - aircraft autonomous integrity monitoring",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9483803058974446",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "540",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the basic principle of RAIM?",
    "answer": "Basic RAIM uses 1 extra satellite over and above the 4 required to give a 3D fix. At a repeating time interval, data from 1 of the 4 satellites is replaced with the spare. If a discrepancy is apparent then an error must be apparent in either the replaced satellite or the spare.\u000b\u000bBy continuously sampling satellites a faulty satellite can be identified and removed from the calculation",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0844704788178205",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "541",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "RAIM with Fault Detection requires how many satellites for a 2D and a 3D fix respectively?",
    "answer": "4 and 5",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5407676179893315",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "542",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "RAIM with Fault Detection and Exclusion requires how many satellites for a 2D and a 3D fix respectively?",
    "answer": "5 and 6\u000b\u000bRAIM may be described as using redundant range measurements to support FD and FDE operation. \u000b\u000bFDE can provide an ongoing RAIM function",
    "ref": "13.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7765877754427492",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "543",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Give a basic description of AAIM?",
    "answer": "This combines satellite technology with more conventional navigation systems and possibly barometric altitude and time. It can be combined with IRS, INS and/or radio fixing.",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6327561717480421",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "544",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe how INS and GPS are good combinations?",
    "answer": "INS is not as instantaneously accurate but it is very reliable and not reliant on outside systems. Satellite is very accurate but when it fails it is lost completely.",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6981027368456125",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "545",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "In terms of AAIM, what does a modern FMS do with the various navigational inputs?",
    "answer": "It uses all available data to form a 'view' of where the aircraft is. The inputs from other systems can identify when the GPS is in error.",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7734898445196451",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "546",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name both types of ABAS and do they provide improved GPS accuracy? or GPS monitoring?",
    "answer": "RAIM and AAIM\u000bThey provide monitoring",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.614107936155051",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "547",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the basic principle of GBAS?",
    "answer": "A ground station measures the signal errors transmitted by satellites and relays measured errors to users to enable raw GPS data to be corrected to a high degree of accuracy.",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.836472132243216",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "548",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What GPS errors can a GBAS system correct for?",
    "answer": "Satellite clocks, ephemeris, ionospheric propagation.",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6006799037568271",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "549",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How is the GPS correction from a GBAS delivered to the user?",
    "answer": "The GPS position correction, precision approach path details and integrity information are delivered to the user over a VHF data link operating in the VOR range from 108 to 118 MHz.",
    "ref": "13.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7440915545448661",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "550",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the range of a GBAS system?",
    "answer": "The VHF data broadcast might be referred to by the acronym VDB and is limited to a range of about 20 miles.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7424447298981249",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "05/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "551",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What 2 services does a GBAS Ground station provide?",
    "answer": "1) Information for guidance in the terminal area\u000b\u000b2) Information for 3 dimensional guidance in the final approach segment.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7981025124900043",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "552",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is a GRAS?",
    "answer": "A ground regional augmentation system\u000b\u000bICAO standards provide the possibility to form a network broadcasting large scale differential corrections.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.6407152800820768",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "553",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What was the old name for GBAS used in the US?",
    "answer": "LAAS - Local Area Augmentation System",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.4319164589978754",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "554",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What term is the GBAS precision approach service normally referred to?",
    "answer": "A GLS approach - meaning GBAS Landing System",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9535508523695172",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "555",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the GLS approach interpretation from the pilots point of view?",
    "answer": "A GLS approach provides guidance in 3 dimensions for final approach segments down to as low as 200'. It is designed to be interpreted in the same way as an ILS requiring no further training.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0222103698179125",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "556",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What's the difference between a GLS and an ILS approach in terms of receiving the signals?",
    "answer": "The VDB frequency for a GLS is selected by a 5 digit channel number instead of a frequency.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1383889522403478",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "557",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are the dimensions/range of the GBAS GLS approach?",
    "answer": "15 NM from threshold, 35 degrees either side of final approach path. There is a further extension out to 20NM and 10 degrees either side.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7538205306045711",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "558",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are the 4 types of Satellite Based Augmentation system (SBAS)?",
    "answer": "Wide Area Augmentation System (WAAS) - developed in the US\u000b\u000bMulti-functional Satellite Augmentation System (MSAS) from Japan\u000b\u000bThe GPS-Aided Augmentation Navigation (GAGAN)system in India\u000b\u000bThe European Navigation Overlay System (EGNOS) in Western Europe and Mediterranean.",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1650529974140226",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "559",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the system architecture for an SBAS system - eg segment types?",
    "answer": "The SBAS systems use the same arrangements as GPS - Ground, Space and User segments consisting of airborne SBAS receivers",
    "ref": "13.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3222504537552595",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "06/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "560",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the 4 (significant) GNSS systems currently operating?",
    "answer": "Navstar GPS (U.S)\u000b\u000bGLONASS (CIS - formerly Soviet Union)\u000b\u000bGalileo - operated by ESA\u000b\u000bBeidou - Chinese.",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4956781244836748",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "561",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the 3 basic elements of a GNSS?",
    "answer": "Space segment - constellation of satellites\u000b\u000bGround segment - eg, control station, antennae, monitor stations \u000b\u000bUser segment - appropriate receivers",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4166173790581525",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "562",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How many satellites in a (notional) constellation of satellites?",
    "answer": "24",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2993456600233912",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "563",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How many orbital planes of satellites are there in Navstar?",
    "answer": "6",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1286005224101245",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "564",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the orbital planes relative to the equator?",
    "answer": "6 orbital planes each at 55 degrees to the equator",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9252396873198449",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "565",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the height of the orbiting satellites in Navstar?",
    "answer": "10,900 NM or 20,200 Km",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9348956975154578",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "566",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the rotational period of the satellites in Navstar?",
    "answer": "One orbit every 12 hours",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4774755686521529",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "567",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How many satellites will be in line of site at any one time?",
    "answer": "5 to 8 satellites will be in line of site at any one time.",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5872029513120651",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "568",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What latitudes north and south do satellite ground tracks go up to?",
    "answer": "55 deg north/south.",
    "ref": "12.1",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3176766359247267",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "569",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Navstar GPS has more satellites than a 'notional' constellation - how many does it have?",
    "answer": "Currently has 31",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0922024212777614",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "570",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Using the United States convention for radion bands, what frequency band do the Satellites transmit in?",
    "answer": "L band",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4675984149798751",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "571",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are the 2 exact frequencies that the GPS satellites transmit on?",
    "answer": "1575.42 MHz L1\u000b\u000b1227.6 MHz L2",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3817793703638016",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "572",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Control of the satellite is maintained by an uplink in what band?",
    "answer": "'S' band",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9712006272748112",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "573",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "The original GPS service provides 2 services - one for military and one for civilian. What is each service referred to as?",
    "answer": "Military: Precise Positioning Service (PPS) which uses both the L1 and L2 signal and transmits a P (precise code) or PY code\u000b\u000bCivilian: Standard Positioning Service (SPS) which uses only L1 signal and known as the course acquisition (C/A)",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9198007020168006",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "575",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is used to control the timing of each satellites transmissions?",
    "answer": "4 on board atomic clocks",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9738450376316904",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "576",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How are the satellites on-board atomic clocks monitored?",
    "answer": "The time signal is received and checked by monitor stations around the world and check against atomic clocks in the master control station in California.(This is the control segment).",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2382443188689648",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "577",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "As well as monitoring the atomic clocks of the satellites, what other function does the control segment achieve?",
    "answer": "Uploading of corrections, database - it will also mark a failed satellite as 'unhealthy'",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2226348961703479",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "578",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Each satellite transmits a unique identifier - describe the type of signal?",
    "answer": "It's a long digital signal modulated on the Satellite carrier wave using Binary Phase Shift Keying (BPSK).\u000b\u000bIt's a pseudo random noise code.",
    "ref": "12.2",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4459204147569835",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "579",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How does the receiving equipment operate, in basic principle?",
    "answer": "The receiver uses its own internal clock to measure how long the message has been in transit and converts the time delay into a distance from the satellite.",
    "ref": "12.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6582292756065726",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "580",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the minimum number of satellites needed for a 2D fix?",
    "answer": "3",
    "ref": "12.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9495520354248584",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "581",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What term can be used to describe the process of using 3 sides of a surface to determine position?",
    "answer": "Trilateration. \u000b\u000bAlthough actually the system us using more than 3 and they're spheres.",
    "ref": "12.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5478131328709424",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "582",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "The clock in the receiver is electronic and not atomic and therefore timing accuracies  (receiver clock bias)can create large errors - how is this problem overcome?",
    "answer": "The receiver iteratively applies corrections to the pseudo ranges until the area of uncertainty is as small as possible. \u000b\u000bThe receiver is then completely synchronised to satellite time.",
    "ref": "12.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.137540350202471",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "583",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the receiver clock error sometimes known as?",
    "answer": "Receiver Clock Bias",
    "ref": "12.3",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4661346697248519",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "584",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "The receiver clock bias correction relies on what other information to be held in the receiver?",
    "answer": "The satellite positions need to be known.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1735751889646053",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "586",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How are the satellite positions entered and updated into the receiving equipment?",
    "answer": "They are downloaded as a second part of the satellite signal called the NAV message.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4322827984578908",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "587",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the timing of the Nav message?",
    "answer": "It is sent in 25 x 30-second date frames. So the whole message takes 12.5 minutes. Individual frames are useful and the information is 'chunked' and therefore still useful if the satellite is not in view for 12.5 minutes.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.996260367333889",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "588",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the timing of the Nav message?",
    "answer": "It is sent in 25 x 30-second date frames. So the whole message takes 12.5 minutes. Individual frames are useful and the information is 'chunked' and therefore still useful if the satellite is not in view for 12.5 minutes.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.658608660567552",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "589",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the 6 items in the NAV message?",
    "answer": "Almanac\u000bEphemeris\u000bSatellite Clock Correction\u000bUTC Correction\u000bIonospheric Model\u000bSatellite Health Status",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5865058996714652",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "590",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What specifically is ephemeris data (part of the GPS NAV Message)?",
    "answer": "Short term position information of the transmitting satellite - valid for 4 hours. More accurate than the date in the almanac.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9697701670229436",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "591",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What specifically is the 'Satellite Clock Correction' - (part of the GPS NAV Message)?",
    "answer": "A correction for the the error in the atomic clocksas detected by the control segment.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1379384668543934",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "592",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Why is there a requirement for UTC Correction in the NAV Message?",
    "answer": "Because the user's receiver requires a UTC for the operator - UTC has 'leap seconds' applied as required. GPS time does not.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5030475948005915",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "593",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the 'ionospheric model' part of the GPS NAV message?",
    "answer": "A database model for the receiver to attempt to correct for the error caused by the delay to the signal as it passes through the ionsophere.",
    "ref": "12.4",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9810026939958334",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "594",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What axes are used within the receiver and what are they referenced to?",
    "answer": "X, Y, Z and Time. They are referenced to the WGS 84 Ellipsoid and is then presented to the user as latitude, longitude and height.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9841220653615892",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "595",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are the 2 methods that GPS receivers compute velocity?",
    "answer": "1) Low end receivers computer change of position over time. Accurate to meters/second\u000b\u000b2) Sophisticated receivers take a doppler shift of the received signal, factor out the speed of the satellite velocity and left with receiver velocity - accurate to centimetres per second.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5041483691893518",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "596",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the 'Time to First Fix' process?",
    "answer": "When the receiver is first turned on, it uses its internal almanac to reference against the satellites it is receiving from, and also references it's last position prior to being switched off.\u000b\u000bIf the receiver has been moved when turned off, it can take 4 to 5 minutes for this process to complete.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.618874060921371",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "597",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How can the 'time to first fix' be reduced?",
    "answer": "By manually entering a position, time and date.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5151724447496235",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "598",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the typical achieved accuracy of raw GPS for civilian users?",
    "answer": "Typically less than 1 metre 95% of the time.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6365907173603773",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "599",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What does UERE stand for?",
    "answer": "User Equivalent Range Errors- \u000b\u000b(this is made up of all the residual errors, that have not been compensated for, as received by the User",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.071564155165106",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "600",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the User Equivalent Range Errors?",
    "answer": "Ionosperic Propagation Delay\u000bSatellite Orbital variations\u000bInstrument/receiver error\u000bMultipath signals\u000bSatellite clock error\u000bSatellite geometry error (DOP)\u000bCoverage Problems.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3630150817334652",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "601",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the User Equivalent Range Errors?",
    "answer": "Ionosperic Propagation Delay\u000bSatellite Orbital variations\u000bInstrument/receiver error\u000bMultipath signals\u000bSatellite clock error\u000bSatellite geometry error (DOP)\u000bCoverage Problems.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7545690177939832",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "602",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "In the context of Ionsopheric propagation delay, which satellites are likely to have the least errors?",
    "answer": "Satellites overhead.\u000b\u000bSatellites on the horizon will have the most error.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3345626057125628",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "603",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How do military receivers correct for ionosperic propagation delay?",
    "answer": "They operate on 2 frequencies - L1 and L2. Therefore, the delays can be compared and a correction computed.",
    "ref": "12.5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1341825197450816",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "604",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How do civilian receivers correct for Ionospheric propagation delay?",
    "answer": "They can only receive on one frequency - L1. Therefore, they do not have L2 to compare with. Therefore a correction is made by a database model/prediction of the ionospheric delay.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.36850262619555",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "605",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are L2C signals?",
    "answer": "Second frequencies are now being provided on L2 alongside the P codes allowing suitable civilian receivers the same accuracy as military receivers.These are called L2C",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4896608050912618",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "606",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What factors can cause Satellite orbital variations - eg, ephemeris error?",
    "answer": "Solar winds, gravitational fluctuations",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6614134232513608",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "607",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How long can satellite orbital variations take to detect?",
    "answer": "Up to 3 hours.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8327518785372376",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "608",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How long can satellite orbital variations take to detect?",
    "answer": "Up to 3 hours.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7586969705298543",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "609",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What are instrument/Receiver errors?",
    "answer": "These can be caused by electrical noise, errors matching pseudo-random signals etc. Accuracy  can be reduced from 1 to 5 metres.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6790056931786239",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "610",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How can multi-path signal errors be reduced?",
    "answer": "By aerial design and software fixes. Errors may still be present at low level in mountainous areas.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2018819600343704",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "611",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe Dilution of Precision?",
    "answer": "This is reduced accuracy when satellites are close together and the cross-cut angle is shallow. It can cause position errors of up to 70m.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9558170726522804",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "612",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "DOP can be expressed as a number in the range 1 to 20. What is a good number and what is poor?",
    "answer": "1 is good\u000b20 is poor",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9352404391393064",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "613",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Why are GPS signals relatively easy to jam?",
    "answer": "They are weak signals derived from satellite batteries- they can be jammed either accidentally or deliberately by transmissions on the same frequency.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1740832030773162",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "614",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What might areas of no GPS coverage be called?",
    "answer": "Wormholes",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4099900564178824",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "615",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "So called 'wormholes' ie areas of no GPS coverage,can be notified, if predictable, by what method?",
    "answer": "NOTAM",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7308074873872101",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "616",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Harmonics of what frequencies might interfere with GPS signals?",
    "answer": "Harmonics of TV broadcasts on UHF frequencies.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7753827422857283",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "617",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Why might truck drivers be relevant to GPS reception?",
    "answer": "Apparently, they use GPS jammers to stop their employers seeing where they are.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2245698911137879",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "618",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Modern aviation receivers can receive how many satellite transmissions?",
    "answer": "Modern receivers are multi-channel and can listen to many transmissions - potentially 200 - 400 channels which means they can listen to all satellites in view, even from multiple constellations.",
    "ref": "12. 5",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.941297685727477",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "619",
    "topic": "GNSS",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What does PRN stand for?",
    "answer": "Pseudo random noise",
    "ref": "",
    "source": "BGS Radio Nav Manual",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0735972798429429",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "07/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1515",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that radio waves travel at the speed of light, which is?",
    "answer": "being approximately 300 000 km/s.\u000b162,000 NM/S",
    "ref": "062.01.01.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2383396052755415",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1516",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define a ‘cycle’?",
    "answer": "a complete series of values of a periodical process.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.840477852616459",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1518",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘frequency?",
    "answer": "The number of cycles occurring in 1 second expressed in Hertz (Hz).",
    "ref": "062.01.01.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0696937604807317",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1519",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘wavelength’?",
    "answer": "The physical distance travelled by a radio wave during one cycle of transmission.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3039590357802808",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1520",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘amplitude’?",
    "answer": "The maximum deflection in an oscillation or wave.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5314735239371657",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1521",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the relationship between wavelength and frequency?",
    "answer": "wavelength (lamda) = speed of light (c) / frequency (f).",
    "ref": "062.01.01.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7482060226611793",
    "notes": "Think speed = distance over tme",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1522",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘phase angle’?",
    "answer": "The fraction of one wavelength expressed in degrees from 000 degrees to 360 degrees .",
    "ref": "062.01.01.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5478954818099737",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1523",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘phase angle difference/shift’:",
    "answer": "The angular difference between the corresponding points of two cycles of equal wavelength, which is measurable in degrees.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.02.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.230547725688666",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1525",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the bands of the frequency spectrum for electromagnetic waves:",
    "answer": "very low frequency (VLF): 3-30 kHz; \u000blow frequency (LF): 30-300 kHz; \u000bmedium frequency (MF): 300-3 000 kHz; \u000bhigh frequency (HF): 3-30 MHz; \u000bvery high frequency (VHF): 30-300 MHz; \u000bultra-high frequency (UHF): 300-3 000 MHz; \u000bsuper high frequency (SHF): 3-30 GHz; \u000bextremely high frequency (EHF): 30-300 GHz.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9716205061413348",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1526",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that when a carrier wave is modulated, the resultant radiation consists of the carrier frequency plus?",
    "answer": "Additional upper and lower sidebands.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3232597718015312",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1527",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that HF meteorological information for aircraft in flight (VOLMET) and HF two-way communication use how many sidebands?",
    "answer": "A single sideband.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8117492166347802",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1528",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the following abbreviations (classifications according to International Telecommunication Union (ITU) regulations) are used for aviation applications:",
    "answer": "N0N: carrier without modulation as used by non-directional radio beacons (NDBs); \u000b\u000bA1A: carrier with keyed Morse code modulation as used by NDBs; \u000b\u000bA2A: carrier with amplitude modulated Morse code as used by NDBs; \u000b\u000bA3E: carrier with amplitude modulated speech used for communication (VHF-COM).",
    "ref": "062.01.01.03.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6087613953277469",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1532",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘carrier wave’:",
    "answer": "The radio wave acting as the carrier or transporter.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0988455871120095",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1533",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘modulation’:",
    "answer": "the technical term for the process of impressing and transporting information by radio waves.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.05.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6012265761382878",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1535",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘amplitude modulation’:",
    "answer": "the information that is impressed onto the carrier wave by altering the amplitude of the carrier.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.06.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0760807693004608",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1536",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘frequency modulation’:",
    "answer": "the information that is impressed onto the carrier wave by altering the frequency of the carrier.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.06.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0914961611852049",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1537",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe ‘pulse modulation’:",
    "answer": "A modulation form used in radar by transmitting short pulses followed by larger interruptions.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.06.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0424985368736088",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1538",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe ‘phase modulation’:",
    "answer": "A modulation form used in GPS where the phase of the carrier wave is reversed.",
    "ref": "062.01.01.06.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4475456499494612",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1541",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘antenna’:",
    "answer": "An antenna or aerial is an electrical device which converts electric power into radio waves, and vice versa.",
    "ref": "062.01.02.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0764568606391549",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1542",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the simplest type of antenna is a?",
    "answer": "Dipole, which is a wire of length equal to one half of the wavelength.",
    "ref": "062.01.02.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1473956718109548",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1543",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an electromagnetic wave always consists of?",
    "answer": "An oscillating electric (E) and an oscillating magnetic (H) field which propagates at the speed of light.",
    "ref": "062.01.02.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8402267196215689",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1544",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the E and H fields are BLANK to each other. The oscillations are BLANK to the propagation direction and are in-phase. Find the single word that replaces both \"blanks\"?",
    "answer": "Perpendicular",
    "ref": "062.01.02.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7348792916163802",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1546",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the polarisation of an electromagnetic wave describes the?",
    "answer": "Orientation of the plane of oscillation of the electrical component of the wave with regard to its direction of propagation.",
    "ref": "062.01.02.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5160831296816468",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1548",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the common different types of directional antennas:",
    "answer": "Loop antenna used in old automatic direction-finding (ADF) receivers; \u000bParabolic antenna used in weather radars; \u000bSlotted planar array used in more modern weather radars.",
    "ref": "062.01.02.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6077622771263123",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1553",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "The ionosphere is the ionised component of the Earth’s upper atmosphere from approximately X to Z km above the surface, which is vertically structured in three regions or layers. What is X and Z?",
    "answer": "X = 60\u000bZ = 400",
    "ref": "062.01.03.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9125665808096528",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1554",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the layers of the ionosphere are named?",
    "answer": "D, E and F layers, and their depth varies with time.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7908275332301854",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1555",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that electromagnetic waves refracted from the E and F layers of the ionosphere are called?",
    "answer": "Sky waves.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9570806855335832",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1556",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain how the different layers of the ionosphere influence wave propagation.",
    "answer": "Most refraction occurs at 125km high in the E layer\u000bSome skywaves refract from the F layer which is above the E layer",
    "ref": "062.01.03.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5682975961826742",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1558",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘ground or surface waves’:",
    "answer": "The electromagnetic waves travelling along the surface of the Earth.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5785105535760522",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1560",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘space waves’:",
    "answer": "The electromagnetic waves travelling through the air directly from the transmitter to the receiver.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7144964351318777",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1562",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that radio waves in VHF, UHF, SHF and EHF propagate as?",
    "answer": "Space waves.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.04.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5850439625792205",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1563",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that radio waves in LF, MF and HF propagate as?",
    "answer": "Surface/ground waves and sky waves.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.04.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5377498660236597",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1565",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the Doppler effect is?",
    "answer": "The phenomenon where the frequency of a wave will increase or decrease if there is relative motion between the transmitter and the receiver.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1240549320355057",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1567",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘skip distance’:",
    "answer": "The distance between the transmitter and the point on the surface of the Earth where the first sky wave return arrives.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.06.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.490272612310946",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1568",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that skip zone/dead space is the?",
    "answer": "Distance between the limit of the surface wave and the sky wave.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.06.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.855603344272822",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1569",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe ‘fading’:",
    "answer": "When a receiver picks up two signals with the same frequency, and the signals will interfere with each other causing changes in the resultant signal strength and polarisation.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.06.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4304554052650929",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1570",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that radio waves in the VHF band and above are limited in range because?",
    "answer": "They are not reflected by the ionosphere and do not have a surface wave.",
    "ref": "062.01.03.06.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2455397178418934",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1572",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that multipath is when the signal arrives at the receiver via?",
    "answer": "More than one path (the signal being reflected from surfaces near the receiver).",
    "ref": "062.01.03.06.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4754971172660588",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1576",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the use of a ground DF.",
    "answer": "Adcock aerial, series of dipoles arranged in a circle. Each will receive a slightly different phase of the incoming signal. The difference in phase indicates where th signal is coming from. \u000b\u000bUses: Bearing information can be provided on request\u000b\u000bQDR - mag bearing from the station (R for radial)\u000bQDM - mag bearing to the station\u000b\u000bBearing accuracy of +/- 5 deg\u000b\u000bVDF Letdown - Pilot interpreted\u000bQGH Letdown - controller interpreted",
    "ref": "062.02.01.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3845534725114703",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1577",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the limitation of range because of the path of the VHF signal.",
    "answer": "Line of sight\u000bNo skywave\u000bNo surface wave\u000bTerrain will mask\u000bSuper-refraction can extend the expected range. This is allowed for in the equation",
    "ref": "062.02.01.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.38233481394127",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1579",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the term ‘QDM’?",
    "answer": "The magnetic bearing to the station.",
    "ref": "062.02.01.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.566997189540416",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1580",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the term ‘QDR’:",
    "answer": "The magnetic bearing from the station.",
    "ref": "062.02.01.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6392451440915465",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1581",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that by using more than one ground station, the position of an aircraft can be determined and transmitted to the pilot.",
    "answer": "This only occurs on 121.5. On this frequency auto triangulation may be available or, depending on height and position manual triangulation may give a position",
    "ref": "062.02.01.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9479004219174384",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1583",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Use the formula:  to calculate the range of radio waves in NM.",
    "answer": "1.23 × sqrt transmitter height in feet plus 1.23 × sqrt receiver height in feet",
    "ref": "062.02.01.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2555131502449512",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1585",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Ground Direction Finding: fixings etc. Explain why synchronous transmissions will cause errors.",
    "answer": "Simultaneous transmissions from other aircraft on same freq lead to erroneous bearings, multipath and reflections.",
    "ref": "062.02.01.04.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9495139750652016",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1586",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the effect of ‘multipath signals’.",
    "answer": "Will cause erroneous bearings",
    "ref": "062.02.01.04.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2039034687913954",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1587",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that VDF information is divided into the following classes according to ICAO Annex 10:",
    "answer": "Class A: accurate to a range within plus/minus 2 degrees ; \u000b\u000bClass B: accurate to a range within plus/minus 5 degrees ; \u000b\u000bClass C: accurate to a range within plus/minus 10 degrees ; \u000b\u000bClass D: accurate to less than Class C.",
    "ref": "062.02.01.04.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0448067667894065",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1590",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the acronym ‘NDB’:",
    "answer": "non-directional radio beacon.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0609860573895275",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1591",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the acronym ‘ADF’:",
    "answer": "Automatic direction-finding equipment.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2578625096939504",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1594",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the NDB operates in which frequency bands?",
    "answer": "LF and MF frequency bands.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5825654556974769",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1595",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the frequency band assigned to aeronautical NDBs according to ICAO Annex 10 is X kHz. What is X?",
    "answer": "190-1750 kHz\u000b\u000bIn Europe they are usually 280 to 530 kHz",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1700704544782638",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1596",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define a ‘locator beacon’:",
    "answer": "An LF/MF NDB used as an aid to final approach usually with a range of 10-25 NM.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7268710369244219",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1597",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that certain commercial radio stations transmit within the frequency band of the NDB.",
    "answer": "eg, commercial stations above 190 kHz",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.730120686814189",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1598",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that according to ICAO Annex 10, an NDB station has an 'BLANK' ground 'BLANK2 system. What are the blanks?",
    "answer": "Automatic and Monitoring (in that order)",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.27235000859946",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1599",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the use of NDBs for navigation.",
    "answer": "ADF's can be shown on:\u000b\u000bOld fixed card RBI (add mag hdg to rel bear gives QDM)\u000bMoving Card RBI\u000bRMI (modern)",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.10",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5158869046717881",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1600",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the procedure to identify an NDB station.",
    "answer": "BFO (beat frequency oscillator) to be switched on for N0N A1A beacons to hear the interruptions that make up the morse ident\u000b\u000bN0N A2A beacons use AM morse code signal so BFO not needed.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.11",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4044696250930429",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1602",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an NDB station emits a N0N/A1A or a N0N/A2A signal.",
    "answer": "A1A uses interruptions of the carrier wave and BFO to create an audible ident\u000b\u000bA2A uses AM morse ident.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.13",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5842219111509621",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1603",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the function of the beat frequency oscillator (BFO).",
    "answer": "It produces a frequency slightly removed from the received frequency and the 2 are then mixed. \u000beg, 400 received, 401 generated\u000b\u000b401 - 400 - 1kHz - this is the beat frequency which is audible.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.01.14",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3982442934066056",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1607",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the types of indicators commonly in use for ADF?",
    "answer": "Electronic display; \u000bradio magnetic indicator (RMI); \u000bfixed-card ADF (radio compass); \u000bmoving-card ADF.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9657431370578704",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1610",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Calculate the true bearing from the compass heading and relative bearing.",
    "answer": "Use of VEML\u000bVariation Least,Magnetic Least\u000b\u000bie, the magnetic heading will be less than the true heading with East variation and vice-versa\u000b\u000bVariation '+' is East\u000bVariation '-' is west\u000b(think of going clockwise wise from North to East - the numbers get more positive like on a clock)",
    "ref": "062.02.02.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2644809554331004",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1611",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Convert the compass bearing into magnetic bearing and true bearing.",
    "answer": "CDMVT\u000b\u000bThis gives the order of corrections\u000b\u000bCompass, deviation, Magnetic, Variation, True",
    "ref": "062.02.02.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2471003215759993",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1614",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the power of the transmitter limits the range of an NDB. Approx what power would a long range NDB require?",
    "answer": "10KW - range 500NM\u000b\u000b1KW - range 1kW",
    "ref": "062.02.02.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3471893314272165",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1615",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the relationship between power and range.",
    "answer": "A coarse formula is:\u000b\u000bMax Range = 3 x sq-root of the power in watts",
    "ref": "062.02.02.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6730397092178464",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1616",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the propagation path of NDB radio waves with respect to the ionosphere and the Earth’s surface.",
    "answer": "Principal propagation is ground/surface wave.\u000b\u000bWeak skywaves can be returned at night (ionosphere less dense and attenuation therefore less)\u000b\u000bHave longer range over the sea due to better surface wave propagation",
    "ref": "062.02.02.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8835312407463789",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1617",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that the interference between sky waves and ground waves leads to ‘fading’.",
    "answer": "Returning skywave is no longer polarised - they strike the top of the loop aerial and give current flow when there should be none. Therefore diminished null, ADF hunts, reduced bearing accuracy\u000b\u000bFading can be heard using the BFO - carrier wave will increase/decrease in volume.\u000b\u000bUnlikely inside 200nm as too close to the beacon for skywaves to return.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.03.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.423783621750772",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1618",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define that the accuracy the pilot has to fly the required NDB bearing in order to be considered established during approach, according to ICAO Doc 8168?",
    "answer": "has to be within plus/minus 5 degrees.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.03.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4048689464107156",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1619",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that there is 'BLANK' warning indication of NDB failure. What is BLANK?",
    "answer": "Blank = no",
    "ref": "062.02.02.03.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0308679095469415",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1621",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain ‘coastal refraction’?",
    "answer": "As a radio wave travelling over land crosses the coast, the wave speeds up over water and the wave front bends.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.04.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9563691602088512",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1622",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘night/twilight effect’?",
    "answer": "The influence of sky waves and ground waves arriving at the ADF receiver with a difference of phase and polarisation which introduce bearing errors.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.04.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4679341581650078",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1623",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that interference from other NDB stations on the same frequency may occur at night due to?",
    "answer": "Sky-wave contamination.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.04.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8990601608529688",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1625",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe diffraction of radio waves in mountainous terrain (mountain effect).",
    "answer": "Multipath effects from reflections cause erroneous readings.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3448016024194658",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1626",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that static radiation energy from what type of cloud may interfere with the radio wave and influence the ADF bearing indication.",
    "answer": "Cumulonimbus",
    "ref": "062.02.02.05.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0572202927432954",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1627",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that the bank angle of the aircraft causes a dip error.",
    "answer": "Not the answer in BGS: \u000bThe bank angle causes the received signal to be in a different plane relative to the antenna.\u000b\u000bIn BGS:\u000bBanking causes the receiver sense aerial to be masked.",
    "ref": "062.02.02.05.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.64365552412346",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1630",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the working principle of VOR using the following general terms: reference phase; variable phase; phase difference.",
    "answer": "Variable phase: The VOR dipole rotates at 30 revs a second creating an 30Hz AM signal. The exact phase of the AM signal differs depending on bearing.\u000b\u000bReference Phase: An FM signal also at 30 Hz\u000b\u000bPhase difference. System designed so at 000 deg, the vari and ref phase are in in-phase. Any other bearing will have a phase difference according to bearing.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.478061709087342",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1631",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the frequency band allocated to VOR according to ICAO Annex 10 is VHF, and the frequencies used are?",
    "answer": "108.0 -117.975 MHz.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7177099231630564",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1632",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that frequencies within the allocated VOR range 108.0-111.975 MHz, which have an odd number in the first decimal place, are used by what system?",
    "answer": "instrument landing system (ILS).",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4166965503245592",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1633",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the following types of VOR are in operation:",
    "answer": "conventional VOR (CVOR): a first-generation VOR station emitting signals by means of a rotating antenna; \u000b\u000bDoppler VOR (DVOR): a second-generation VOR station emitting signals by means of a combination of fixed antennas utilising the Doppler principle; \u000b\u000ben-route VOR for use by IFR traffic; \u000b\u000bterminal VOR (TVOR): a station with a shorter range used as part of the approach and departure structure \u000b\u000btest VOR (VOT): a VOR station emitting a signal to test VOR indicators in an aircraft.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9832951268181204",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1635",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the three main components of VOR airborne equipment:",
    "answer": "the antenna; the receiver; the indicator.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1327946758829057",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1636",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the identification of a VOR in terms of Morse-code letters and additional plain text.",
    "answer": "3 letter morse ident modulated at 1020Hz every 10 seconds. If applicable, the DME ident will be 1350 Hz every 40 seconds.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.363328920211643",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1637",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that according to ICAO Annex 10, a VOR station has an automatic ground monitoring system.",
    "answer": "ICAO Annexe 10 requires monitoring to ensure accuracy of + / - 1 degree",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9413913199678065",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1638",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that failure of the VOR station to stay within the required limits can cause the removal of identification and navigation components from the carrier or radiation to cease.",
    "answer": "If out of limits, the transmitter is shut down, standby transmitter used. Shutdown will also happen if signal strength drops by more than 15%. \u000b\u000bWhen out of service, the Ident will be a continuous tone.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.01.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1032379465177655",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1641",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Read off the angular displacement in relation to a preselected radial on a horizontal situation indicator (HSI) or omnibearing indicator (OBI).",
    "answer": "Full scale deflection = 10 degrees\u000b\u000bHalf scale deflection is the limit for an approach - ie, 5 degrees",
    "ref": "062.02.03.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7218091343529521",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1642",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the use of the TO/FROM indicator in order to determine aircraft position relative to the VOR considering also the heading of the aircraft.",
    "answer": "On an HSI, this is different to To/From indicator on the OBI - because there is a compass input on the HSI this always points to the beacon.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2590507855638861",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1645",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that when converting a VOR radial into a true bearing, the variation at either the aircraft of the VOR station has to be taken into account. Which is it?",
    "answer": "Variation at the VOR",
    "ref": "062.02.03.02.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5621820301748812",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1648",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define that the accuracy the pilot has to fly the required bearing in order to be considered established on a VOR track when flying approach procedures,",
    "answer": "According to ICAO Doc 8168, has to be within the half-full scale deflection of the required track.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.04.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9602483161725106",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1649",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that due to reflections from terrain, radials can be bent and lead to wrong or fluctuating indications, which is called?",
    "answer": "‘Scalloping’.",
    "ref": "062.02.03.04.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6357886539772153",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1652",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "The DME operates in which band?",
    "answer": "UHF",
    "ref": "062.02.04.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2915785331279039",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1653",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the system comprises two basic components?",
    "answer": "The aircraft component: the interrogator; \u000bthe ground component: the transponder.",
    "ref": "062.02.04.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9746385049074888",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1654",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the principle of distance measurement using DME in terms of a timed transmission from the interrogator and reply from the transponder on BLANK frequencies. What is 'BLANK'?",
    "answer": "'Different' frequencies",
    "ref": "062.02.04.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5578212277032435",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1655",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that the distance measured by DME is slant range or plan range?",
    "answer": "Slant Range",
    "ref": "062.02.04.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7117037530988455",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1661",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that when identifying a DME station co-located with a VOR station, the identification signal with the higher-tone frequency is?",
    "answer": "The DME which identifies itself approximately every 40 seconds.",
    "ref": "062.02.04.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9182010544463992",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1662",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Calculate ground distance from given slant range and altitude.",
    "answer": "Pythagorus",
    "ref": "062.02.04.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2352415658533573",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1663",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the use of DME to fly a DME arc in accordance with ICAO Doc 8168 Volume 1.",
    "answer": "Single DME range can be used as part of a procedure keeping the aircraft at a constant range from the beacon.  This is a DME Arc\u000b\u000bWhen a DME arc is used to join a hold, it may only be followed by a sector 1 or 3 join.",
    "ref": "062.02.04.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3884611786343157",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1664",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that a DME system may have a ground speed (GS) and time to station read-out combined with the DME read-out.",
    "answer": "Only accurate flying to or from the beacon at some range - ideally greater than the aircraft height in 1000s of feet.",
    "ref": "062.02.04.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2277335883118212",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1666",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why a ground station can generally respond to a maximum of 100 aircraft.",
    "answer": "The ground equipment has limited capacity and can handle 2700 pulses a second. This equates to 18 searching aircraft or 112 locked on. In practice this averages to about 100.",
    "ref": "062.02.04.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2707597902044653",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1667",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain which aircraft will be denied a DME range first when more than 100 interrogations are being made.",
    "answer": "The 100 strongest signals are serviced (not necessarily the closest)",
    "ref": "062.02.04.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0402849917300045",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1669",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Factors affecting range and accuracy",
    "answer": "Pre Jan 1989 accuracy of 0.25 NM plus 1.25% slant range\u000b\u000bPost Jan 1989\u000bSlant range error less than 0.2NM on 95% of occasions.\u000b\u000bIt's the most accurate ground based nav aid.",
    "ref": "062.02.04.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1553384694270789",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1670",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why the GS read-out from a DME can be less than the actual GS, and is zero when flying a DME arc.",
    "answer": "Only accurate flying to/from a DME",
    "ref": "062.02.04.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1750683705322444",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1673",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the three main components of an ILS:",
    "answer": "the localiser (LOC); the glide path (GP); range information (markers or DME).",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0430042590014636",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1674",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the site locations of the ILS components:",
    "answer": "the LOC antenna should be located on the extension of the runway centre line at the stop-end; \u000b\u000bthe GP antenna should be locate beyond the runway threshold, laterally displaced to the side of the runway centre line.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3399220104329288",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1675",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that marker beacons produce radiation patterns for what purpose?",
    "answer": "To indicate predetermined distances from the threshold along the ILS GP.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5640460313297808",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1676",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that ILS marker beacons are sometimes replaced by?",
    "answer": "a DME paired with the LOC frequency.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1429178295657038",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1677",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that in the ILS LOC frequency assigned band 108.0-111.975 MHz, only frequencies which have an BLANK number in the first decimal are ILS LOC frequencies. What is BLANK?",
    "answer": "Blank = Odd",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4857410681433976",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1678",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the GP operates in the what band?",
    "answer": "UHF",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7990108304657042",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1680",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "How is the UHF GP frequency selected?",
    "answer": "Automatically by being paired with the LOC frequency.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7410232736729084",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1681",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that both the LOC and the GP antenna radiates side lobes (false beams) which can give rise to?",
    "answer": "False centre-line and false GP indication.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1171635338105261",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1682",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that the back beam from the LOC antenna may be used as a published procedure - is this a ‘non-precision approach’ or a 'precision approach'?",
    "answer": "‘non-precision approach’.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.10",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7494024015031755",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1683",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the recommended GP is X degrees .",
    "answer": "X = 3\u000b\u000b(I think they mean 'recommended' in the context of designing an approach - not alluding to some kind of choice for the pilot.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.11",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1980521124787629",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1684",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the frequency, modulation and identification assigned to all marker beacons?",
    "answer": "All marker beacons operate on 75-MHz carrier frequency. The modulation frequencies of the audio are: outer marker: low; middle marker: medium; inner marker: high. The audio frequency modulation (for identification) is the continuous modulation of the audio frequency and is keyed as follows: outer marker: 2 dashes per second continuously; middle marker: a continuous series of alternate dots and dashes; inner marker: 6 dots per second continuously. The outer-marker cockpit indicator is coloured blue, the middle marker amber, and the inner marker white.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.12",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.652001696638763",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1685",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the final-approach area contains a fix or facility that permits verification of the ILS GP-altimeter relationship. Which item normally serves this purpose?",
    "answer": "The outer marker or DME is usually used for this purpose.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.01.13",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7201177482493222",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1689",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is the principle function of the LOC and GP monitoring system?",
    "answer": "It monitors any shift in the LOC and GP mean course line or reduction in signal strength.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6914014187641442",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1690",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What will cause warning flags to appear for both the LOC and the GP?",
    "answer": "if the received signal strength is below a threshold value?",
    "ref": "062.02.05.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3633311744779349",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1691",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the circumstances in which warning flags will appear for both the LOC and the GP?",
    "answer": "Absence of the carrier frequency; \u000babsence of the modulation simultaneously; \u000bthe percentage modulation of the navigation signal reduced to 0.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5547176534309983",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1692",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Interpret the indications on a CDI and an HSI:",
    "answer": "Full-scale deflection of the CDI needle corresponds to approximately 2.5 degrees displacement from the ILS centre line; \u000b\u000bFull-scale deflection on the GP corresponds to approximately 0.7 degrees from the ILS GP centre line.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.02.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2597468364983797",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1694",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the setting of the course pointer of an HSI and the course selector of an omnibearing indicator (OBI) for front-beam and back-beam approaches.",
    "answer": "Use the HSI in the correct/logical sense depending on the ILS beam being ahead or behind you.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.02.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2661783276125788",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1696",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Sketch the standard coverage area of the LOC and GP with angular sector limits in degrees and distance limits from the transmitter:",
    "answer": "LOC coverage area is 10 degrees on either side of the centre line to a distance of 25 NM from the runway, and 35 degrees on either side of the centre line to a distance of 17 NM from the runway; \u000b\u000bGP coverage area is 8 degrees on either side of the centre line to a distance of minimum 10 NM from the runway.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6579737197607756",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1699",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the following ILS operation categories:",
    "answer": "Category I; Category II; Category IIIA; Category IIIB; Category IIIC.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.04.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1674664006568491",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1700",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that all Category III ILS operations guidance information is provided from where?",
    "answer": "the coverage limits of the facility to, and along, the surface of the runway.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.04.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6597527740523219",
    "notes": "Describe airfield features",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1702",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the following in accordance with ICAO Doc 8168: the accuracy the pilot has to fly the ILS LOC to be considered established on an ILS track is?",
    "answer": "Is within the half-full scale deflection of the required track; \u000b\u000bThe aircraft has to be established within the half-scale deflection of the LOC before starting descent on the GP; \u000b\u000bThe pilot has to fly the ILS GP to a maximum of half-scale fly-up deflection of the GP in order to stay in protected airspace.\u000b\u000b(Careful with questions here: MORE THAN half scale? or at Half scale? or WITHIN half-scale. The questions can be sneaky)",
    "ref": "062.02.05.04.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3410067679360509",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1703",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "If a pilot deviates by more than half-course deflection on the LOC or by more than half-dot deflection on the GP, then what action should they take?",
    "answer": "An immediate go-around should be executed because obstacle clearance may no longer be guaranteed.\u000b\u000b(Be careful with sneaky questions - MORE THAN or AT half-scale etc).",
    "ref": "062.02.05.04.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0388731262646615",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1704",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe ILS beam bends?",
    "answer": "As deviations from the nominal LOC and GP respectively which can be assessed by flight test. \u000b\u000bie, slight (propagation?) bends that can be coped with - caused by loacl effects etc.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.04.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0847761258482933",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1705",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that multipath interference is caused by?",
    "answer": "Reflections from objects within the ILS coverage area.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.04.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5683314227499068",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1707",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the ‘ILS-critical area?",
    "answer": "An area of defined dimensions around the LOC and GP antennas where vehicles, including aircraft, are excluded during all ILS operations.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5238651605322957",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1708",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define the ‘ILS-sensitive area’:",
    "answer": "an area extending beyond the ILS-critical area where the parking or movement of vehicles, including aircraft, is controlled to prevent the possibility of unacceptable interference to the ILS signal during ILS operations.",
    "ref": "062.02.05.05.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.240002921782434",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1711",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the principle of MLS operation?",
    "answer": "Horizontal course guidance during the approach; vertical guidance during the approach; horizontal guidance for departure and missed approach; DME (DME/P) distance; transmission of special information regarding the system and the approach conditions.\u000b\u000bThe scan operates 'To' and 'Fro' - it will scan the aircraft twice and the relative time interval between each respective 'hit' is relative to position - ie, even interval means the aircraft is centred\u000b\u000b(I think of a wonky pendulum on a clock giving an uneven tick-tock sound)",
    "ref": "062.02.06.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7785044857300818",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1712",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that MLS operates in which band on any one of BLANK channels, on assigned frequencies?",
    "answer": "SHF \u000bBlank = 200",
    "ref": "062.02.06.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4690668541006744",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1713",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the reason why MLS can be installed at aerodromes where, as a result of the effects of surrounding buildings or terrain, ILS siting is difficult.",
    "answer": "It's more convenient and cheaper to install.",
    "ref": "062.02.06.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9650398297235367",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1715",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Interpret the MLS display of airborne equipment designed to continuously show the position of the aircraft in relation to a preselected course and glide path, along with distance information, during approach and departure.",
    "answer": "Same display equipment as ILS?",
    "ref": "062.02.06.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5442952797748148",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1716",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that segmented MLS approaches can be carried out with a presentation with two cross bars directed by what system?",
    "answer": "A (FMC) computer which has been programmed with the approach to be flown. \u000b\u000bSegmented MLS approaches are not flown manually (I don't think)",
    "ref": "062.02.06.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3084277375601232",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1717",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Illustrate that MLS segmented and curved approaches can only be executed with what type of DME?",
    "answer": "DME/P installed.\u000b\u000bThis is modified version of normal DME only used with MLS gives range accuracies of +/- 100'",
    "ref": "062.02.06.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8078942568972707",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1718",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why aircraft are equipped with a multimode receiver (MMR) in order to be able to receive ILS, MLS and GPS.",
    "answer": "I think this is to reduce equipment and training for crew - ie, the same display is used.",
    "ref": "062.02.06.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1328455414623022",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1719",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why MLS without DME/P gives an ILS lookalike straight-line approach.",
    "answer": "Answer not found - probably this is actually a test of the accuracies of the respective systems:\u000b\u000bDME/P = +/- 100'\u000bDME = +/- 0.5NM\u000b\u000bWithout DME/P the MLS basically can only give the same as ILS",
    "ref": "062.02.06.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4523497591726481",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1721",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the MLS coverage area for the approach direction as being within a sector",
    "answer": "Of plus/minus 40 degrees of the centre line out to a range of 20 NM from the threshold (according to ICAO Annex 10).",
    "ref": "062.02.06.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.289432147052139",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1727",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the range of a radar depends on?",
    "answer": "Pulse repetition frequency (PRF), pulse length, pulse power, height of aircraft, height of antenna and frequency used.",
    "ref": "062.03.01.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2448102650232612",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1730",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that primary radar provides?",
    "answer": "bearing and distance of targets.",
    "ref": "062.03.02.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6991418125107884",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1731",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that primary ground radar is used to?",
    "answer": "Detect aircraft that are not equipped with a secondary radar transponder.",
    "ref": "062.03.02.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9579347455874084",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1736",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the two main tasks of the weather radar in respect of weather and navigation.",
    "answer": "1 Main task: Primary purpose is to detect thunderstorms (and by inference, severe turbulence)\u000b\u000b2 main task: ground mapping as a navigation aid",
    "ref": "062.03.03.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2071780143305659",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1737",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that modern weather radars employ frequencies that give wavelengths of about X cm that reflect best on wet hailstones. What is X?",
    "answer": "X = 3cm",
    "ref": "062.03.03.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.401128735858947",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1738",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the AWR antenna is stabilised in the horizontal plane with signals from?",
    "answer": "The aircraft’s attitude reference system.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2691536345519125",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1739",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the radar beam used for weather detection?",
    "answer": "The cone-shaped pencil beam of about 3 to 5 degrees beam width",
    "ref": "062.03.03.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4400963922962546",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1741",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the functions of the following different controls on the radar control panel:",
    "answer": "off/on switch; function switch with WX, WX plus T and MAP modes; gain-control setting (auto/manual); tilt/autotilt switch.\u000b\u000bWx - Weather\u000bWx+T - weather and turbulence\u000bMap - ground mapping mode\u000bTilt - tilt of the beam set auto or manually. And in accordance with company policy. Lots of questions about tilting it up before take-off to see into the climb out area etc. \u000b\u000bPWS - Protective Wind Shear detection ls happens below 2300'",
    "ref": "062.03.03.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5837583444081247",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1742",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name, for areas of differing reflection intensity, the colour gradations?",
    "answer": "(green, yellow, red and magenta) indicating the increasing intensity of precipitation.\u000b\u000bMental note - there is no amber.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2797443498857319",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1743",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "AWR: State the use of azimuth-marker lines and range lines in respect of the relative bearing and the distance to a thunderstorm on the screen.",
    "answer": "Not sure I can find a BGS answer to this - I presume it's just a scale indicating relative bearings, distances etc - use of range settings to see beyond bad weather, blind alleys, unknown weather behind strong returns etc.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2361077978275716",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1745",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain how the radar is used for weather detection and for mapping (range, tilt and gain, if available).",
    "answer": "Many factors put simply:\u000b\u000bTilt up pre-take off\u000b\u000bCruise zero tilt or 1 degree down means at 80NM will be looking 20000' down (80NM is also one of the range rings on the EFIS)\u000b\u000bDescent or low level - tilt slightly up to avoid ground clutter.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1858640532009304",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1746",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Errors, accuracy, limitations",
    "answer": "Best at detecting, in order?\u000b\u000bWet hail\u000bRain\u000bWest snow\u000bDry hail\u000bDry snow\u000bDrizzle\u000b\u000bThink Microwave - it's matched to water droplets in liquid state hence the order is basically wet dense, dry dense, small light.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8448903621174395",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1747",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why AWR should be used with extreme caution when on the ground.",
    "answer": "RADHAZ to people",
    "ref": "062.03.03.04.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7177716884762049",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1749",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the danger of the area behind heavy rain (shadow area) where no radar waves will penetrate.",
    "answer": "It doesn't necessarily mean the area is clear of weather. ie, intense returns are masking weather behind.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7056805291213095",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1750",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe appropriate tilt settings in relation to altitude and thunderstorms.",
    "answer": "Tilt up pre-take off\u000b\u000bCruise zero tilt or 1 degree down means at 80NM will be looking 20000' down (80NM is also one of the range rings on the EFIS)\u000b\u000bDescent or low level - tilt slightly up to avoid ground clutter.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.05.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.923139119055122",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1751",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why a thunderstorm may not be detected when the tilt is set too high.",
    "answer": "The tops of the clouds are mainly Ice which are not easily detected. Therefore the wet/rain needs to be detected which are further down in the CB",
    "ref": "062.03.03.05.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7904936987906694",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1752",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "AWR - Application for navigation",
    "answer": "Use of ground features can be detected on the AWR in mapping mode. Older systems could theoretically be updated with a mapping/radar fix from a known point of land.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0860277358442545",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1753",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the navigation function of the radar in the mapping mode.",
    "answer": "Use of ground features can be detected on the AWR in mapping mode. Older systems could theoretically be updated with a mapping/radar fix from a known point of land.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.06.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6213551107794046",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1754",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Describe the use of the weather radar to avoid a thunderstorm (Cb).",
    "answer": "Use of tilt to detect the wet/rain part of the cloud. Interpretation of the display. Masking issues, etc. Use of gain to help with interpretation of display.",
    "ref": "062.03.03.06.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2052805703133345",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1755",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain how turbulence (not CAT) can be detected by a modern weather radar.",
    "answer": "This works by use of a doppler radar that is sensitive to the horizontal movements of water droplets.Large irregular areas of horizontal movement = turbulence. \u000b\u000bUse the WX/T or WX/Turb mode\u000b\u000bDoesn't detect CAT",
    "ref": "062.03.03.06.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9358753799460828",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1756",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain how wind shear can be detected by a modern weather radar?",
    "answer": "Works below 2300'\u000b\u000bSimilar principle to turbulence detection - ie, doppler radar sensitive to horizontal movement. Detects microbursts etc.  \u000b\u000bHas an audio warning \"WIND SHEAR AHEAD\"",
    "ref": "062.03.03.06.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.01057805493474",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1759",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the ATC SSR system is based on?",
    "answer": "The replies provided by the airborne transponders in response to interrogations from the ATC secondary radar.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9301248556002976",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1761",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an airborne transponder provides?",
    "answer": "Coded-reply signals in response to interrogation signals from the ground secondary radar and from aircraft equipped with traffic alert and collision avoidance system (TCAS).",
    "ref": "062.03.04.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3112742034718394",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1762",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the advantages of secondary surveillance radar (SSR) over a primary radar?",
    "answer": "Range and collected information due to transponder principal information and active participation of the aircraft.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6703162593767047",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1764",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the SSR interrogator transmits its interrogations in the form of?",
    "answer": "A series of pulse pairs.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9046782762743532",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1765",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the interrogation modes?",
    "answer": "Mode A;  4096 codes\u000b\u000bMode C; Alt readout as calculated by ADC\u000b\u000bMode S.16 million 24 bit aircraft addresses",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2215658542700112",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1766",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the interrogation frequency and the reply frequency are different.",
    "answer": "Ground sends out 2 pulses on 1030MHz\u000b\u000bAircraft responds with longer train of pulses on 1090MHz",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6616281708702445",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1767",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that the decoding of the time interval between the pulse pairs determines the operating mode of the transponder:",
    "answer": "Mode A: 8 micro secs\u000bMode C: 21 micro secs\u000b\u000bMode S: selection of aircraft address and transmission of flight data for the ground surveillance.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5962390997447073",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1768",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that Mode A designation is a sequence of?",
    "answer": "Four digits which can be manually selected from 4096 available codes.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4754028897732496",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1769",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that in Mode C reply, the pressure altitude is reported in X-ft increments. What is X?",
    "answer": "100' increments.\u000b\u000b(Note Mode S will report in 25' increments).",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2354132956825196",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1770",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that in addition to the information provided, on request from ATC, a special position identification (SPI) pulse can be transmitted but only when?",
    "answer": "As a result of a manual selection by the pilot (IDENT button).",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0377857852727174",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1771",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the need for compatibility of Mode S with Mode A and C.",
    "answer": "They operate on the same frequencies and are backwards compatible with Mode A and C",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.976780405268073",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1773",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that Mode S interrogation contains either the aircraft address, selective call or all-call address.",
    "answer": "I didn't find a specific reference to this in BGS notes.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.10",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2747049862518906",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1774",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that every aircraft is allocated an ICAO aircraft address, which is BLANK-BLANK into the Mode S transponder (Mode S address).What is the hyphenated blanks?",
    "answer": "Hard-coded",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.11",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6340957432985306",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1776",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that Mode S can provide enhanced vertical tracking, using a X-ft altitude increment. What is X?",
    "answer": "X = 25'",
    "ref": "062.03.04.02.13",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4522476680576801",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1780",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State which information can be presented on the ATC display system?",
    "answer": "pressure altitude; flight level; flight number or aircraft registration number; GS.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2434392469003796",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1781",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the use and function of the selector modes?",
    "answer": "OFF, Standby, ON (Mode A), ALT (Mode A, C and S), TEST, and of the reply lamp.",
    "ref": "062.03.04.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0028829798102378",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "electrical,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1787",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that there are four main GNSSs. These are:",
    "answer": "USA NAVigation System with Timing And Ranging Global Positioning System (NAVSTAR GPS); \u000b\u000bRussian GLObal NAvigation Satellite System (GLONASS); \u000b\u000bEuropean Galileo (under construction); \u000b\u000bChinese BeiDou (under construction).",
    "ref": "062.06.01.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3977867090143263",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1791",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that there are currently two modes of GPS operation:",
    "answer": "Standard positioning service (SPS) for civilian users, \u000b\u000bPrecise positioning service (PPS) for authorised users.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.535305236466229",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1793",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Name the three GNSS segments as follow?",
    "answer": "Space segment; control segment; user segment.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2229430666193366",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1795",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that each satellite broadcasts ranging signals on two UHF frequencies, these are known as?",
    "answer": "L1 and L2.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7966916719451546",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1796",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that SPS is a positioning and timing service provided on?",
    "answer": "frequency L1.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4804854765534401",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1798",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the satellites transmit a coded signal used for?",
    "answer": "Ranging, identification (satellite individual PRN code), timing and navigation.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8913559233769774",
    "notes": "4 things",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1799",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "GNSS: State that the navigation message contains?",
    "answer": "Satellite clock correction parameters; Universal Time Coordinated (UTC) parameters; an ionospheric model; satellite health data.\u000b\u000bBGS also says almanac and ephemeris",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7036656686104834",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1800",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an ionospheric model is used to calculate?",
    "answer": "The time delay of the signal travelling through the ionosphere.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.264663481619209",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1801",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that two codes are transmitted on the L1 frequency, namely?",
    "answer": "a coarse acquisition (C/A) code \u000b\u000band a \u000b\u000bprecision (P) code. The P code is not used for standard positioning service (SPS).",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.10",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4609242626465857",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1802",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that satellites are equipped with what type of clocks which allow the system to keep very accurate time reference.",
    "answer": "Atomic",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.11",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3398117935284972",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1804",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the control segment comprises:",
    "answer": "A master control station; a ground antenna; monitoring stations.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.12",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0495707127265632",
    "notes": "3 sub-sections",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1805",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the control segment provides?",
    "answer": "Monitoring of the constellation status; correction of orbital parameters; navigation data uploading.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.13",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7770237145014107",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1807",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that GNSS supplies what to the User segment?",
    "answer": "three-dimensional position fixes and speed data, plus a precise time reference.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.14",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3243112214840948",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1808",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that a GNSS receiver is able to determine the distance to a satellite by determining?",
    "answer": "The difference between the time of transmission by the satellite and the time of reception.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.15",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5607471605762839",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1809",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the initial distance calculated to the satellites is called pseudo-range because?",
    "answer": "The difference between the GNSS receiver time and the satellite time references initially creates an erroneous range.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.16",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9692646428011356",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1810",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that each range defines a sphere with its centre where?",
    "answer": "At the satellite.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.17",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6888243393041193",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1811",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that there are four unknown parameters (x, y, z and Delta t) (receiver clock error) which require the measurement of ranges to X different satellites in order to get the position. What is X?",
    "answer": "X = 4",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.18",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3989465571939944",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1813",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the receiver is able to calculate aircraft ground speed using?",
    "answer": "The space vehicle (SV) Doppler frequency shift \u000b\u000bOr the change in receiver position over time.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.20",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4419290963560343",
    "notes": "2 methods",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1815",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define ‘receiver autonomous integrity monitoring (RAIM)’ as a technique that ensures the integrity of the provided data by?",
    "answer": "using redundant measurements.\u000b\u000bie, extra satellites",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.21",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5656781406141818",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1816",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RAIM is achieved by?",
    "answer": "Consistency checks among range measurements.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.22",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2406612136401236",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1817",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that basic RAIM requires X satellites. A Yth one is for isolating a faulty satellite from the navigation solution. X and Y are numbers - what are they?",
    "answer": "X = 5\u000bY = 6",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.23",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2127324189059436",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1818",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that agreements have been concluded between the appropriate agencies for the compatibility and interoperability by any approved user of?",
    "answer": "NAVSTAR and GLONASS systems.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.24",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4729125839658081",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1819",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the different GNSSs use different data with respect to reference systems, orbital data, and navigation services.",
    "answer": "My  notes: this has to be the case - they are in different orbits, positions etc.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.02.25",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5588765311986208",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1821",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the most significant factors that affect accuracy?",
    "answer": "ionospheric propagation delay; \u000bdilution of precision; \u000bsatellite clock error; \u000bsatellite orbital variations; \u000bmultipath.\u000b\u000b(wrong position in orbit, , satellites not ideally spaced, wrong time, wayward signal).",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2306543826125562",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1822",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that a user equivalent range error (UERE) can be computed from all these (ie, the significant errors) factors.",
    "answer": "All the erros of satellite:\u000b\u000bIonospheric Propagation\u000bSatellite Orbital variations\u000bInst/receiver error\u000bMultipath signals\u000bSatellite clock error\u000bGDOP\u000bCoverage problems",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5304821981117129",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1823",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the error from the ionospheric propagation delay (IPD) can be reduced by?",
    "answer": "modelling, using a model of the ionosphere, \u000b\u000bor can almost be eliminated by using two frequencies.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7939311102963984",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1824",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the most significant error is?",
    "answer": "Ionospheric delay",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9004003386944531",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1825",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that dilution of precision arises from?",
    "answer": "the geometry and number of satellites in view. It is called geometric dilution of precision (GDOP).",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1192646333947777",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1826",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the UERE in combination with the geometric dilution of precision (GDOP) allows for?",
    "answer": "An estimation of position accuracy.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5573701462708414",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1827",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that errors in the satellite orbits are due to?",
    "answer": "Solar winds; gravitation of the Sun and the Moon.",
    "ref": "062.06.01.03.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.698533033952117",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1830",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the principle of a GBAS?",
    "answer": "To measure on the ground the errors in the signals transmitted by GNSS satellites and relay the measured errors to the user for correction.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7717843255959451",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1831",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the ICAO GBAS standard is based on this technique through the use of a data link in the?",
    "answer": "VHF band of ILS-VOR systems (108-118 MHz).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3902196544222533",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1832",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that for a GBAS station the coverage is about?",
    "answer": "20 NM.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5642245085909963",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1833",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that GBAS provides information for guidance in what 2 areas?",
    "answer": "The terminal area, and for three-dimensional guidance in the final approach segment (FAS) by transmitting the FAS data block.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9211457478813828",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1834",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that one GBAS ground station can support all the aircraft subsystems within its coverage providing the aircraft with approach data, corrections and integrity information for GNSS satellites in view via a?",
    "answer": "VHF data broadcast (VDB).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7481611240655184",
    "notes": "Type of broadcast",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1835",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the minimum software designed GBAS coverage area is?",
    "answer": "10 degrees on either side of the final approach path to a distance between 15 and 20 NM, and 35 degrees on either side of the final approach path up to a distance of 15 NM.\u000b\u000b\u000b\u000bSimilar to ILS but not quite\u000bFor ref, ILS is 10 deg out to 25NM and 35 deg out to 17NM",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0488523198291659",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1836",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that outside the GBAS coverage area the FAS data of GBAS is not used.",
    "answer": "Note: FAS = Final Approach Segment",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0824759327806532",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1837",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that GBAS based on GPS is sometimes called?",
    "answer": "local area augmentation system (LAAS).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1763592483475804",
    "notes": "older term in the U.S",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1838",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that a GBAS-based approach is called a?",
    "answer": "GLS approach (GLS-GNSS landing system).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.01.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1101939263753593",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1840",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the principle of an SBAS?",
    "answer": "To measure on the ground the errors in the signals received from the satellites and transmit differential corrections and integrity messages for navigation satellites.\u000b\u000bie, it uses satellites to broadcast corrections and not a ground VHF broadcast.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8368877465836704",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1841",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the SBAS frequency band of the data link is: identical? or different? to that of the GPS signals.",
    "answer": "It's identical",
    "ref": "062.06.02.02.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2889384478330612",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1845",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that SBAS allows the implementation of three-dimensional Type A and Type B approaches. What are these?",
    "answer": "Type A and B are old ICAO terms more commonly known as APV (approaches with vertical guidance)\u000b\u000bType A DH not less than 250'\u000bTybe B DH not less than 200'",
    "ref": "062.06.02.02.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6748075978830457",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1846",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the following examples of SBAS?",
    "answer": "European Geostationary Navigation Overlay Service (EGNOS) in western Europe and the Mediterranean; \u000b\u000bwide area augmentation system (WAAS) in the USA;\u000b\u000bmulti-functional transport satellite (MTSAT)-based augmentation system (MSAS) in Japan; \u000b\u000bGPS and geostationary earth orbit augmented navigation (GAGAN) in India.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.02.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3461826308630407",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1847",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that SBAS is designed to significantly improve what?",
    "answer": "accuracy and integrity.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.02.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1188850402832031",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1848",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that integrity and safety are improved by alerting SBAS users within X seconds if a GPS malfunction occurs. What is X?",
    "answer": "X = 6",
    "ref": "062.06.02.02.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1095624943263828",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1851",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the principle of ABAS?",
    "answer": "to use redundant elements within the GPS constellation (e.g. multiplicity of distance measurements to various satellites) or the combination of GNSS measurements with those of other navigation sensors (such as inertial systems) in order to develop integrity control.",
    "ref": "062.06.02.04.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3917342922650277",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1852",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the type of ABAS using only GNSS information is named?",
    "answer": "Receiver autonomous integrity monitoring (RAIM).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.04.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9699933985248208",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1853",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that a system using information from additional onboard sensors is named?",
    "answer": "Aircraft autonomous integrity monitoring (AAIM).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.04.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0628980640321969",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1854",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain that the typical sensors used for AAIM are?",
    "answer": "barometric altimeter and inertial reference system (IRS).",
    "ref": "062.06.02.04.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9519264982081947",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1858",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the factors used to define area navigation (RNAV) or required navigation performance (RNP) system performance requirements?",
    "answer": "Accuracy, integrity and continuity.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6352419299073517",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1859",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that these RNAV and RNP systems are necessary to optimise the utilisation of available airspace.",
    "answer": "ie, more efficient use through improved accuracy",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4045543600805104",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1860",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "It is necessary for flight crew and ATC to be aware of the on-board RNAV or RNP system capabilities in order to determine whether the performance of the RNAV or RNP system is appropriate for?",
    "answer": "the specific airspace requirements.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.531221707817167",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1862",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define continuity as the capability of the system to perform its function without...?",
    "answer": "Unscheduled interruptions during the intended operation.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0581302838400006",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1863",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Define integrity as a measure of the BLANK that can be placed in the correctness of the information supplied by the total system. What is 'BLANK'?",
    "answer": "Blank = Trust\u000b\u000bIntegrity includes the ability of a system to provide timely and valid alerts to the user.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2111905068159103",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1864",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that, unlike conventional navigation, PBN is not sensor-specific.",
    "answer": "I find this confusing as GPS is a sensor receiving radio information the same as any other sensor. However, I think it means it doesn't require specific land-based radio aids.ie, frequent tuning, and retuning to aids as the flight progresses etc",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.248939246404916",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1865",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Explain the difference between raw data and computed dat?",
    "answer": "Raw data, eg a VOR signal displayed o an indicator\u000b\u000bComputed data: integrated data displayed/used in a position and navigation system.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3554928130470216",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1866",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "In PBN, Define availability as?",
    "answer": "The percentage of time (annually) during which the system is available for use.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.01.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9659879910759628",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1868",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the components of PBN as navigational aid (NAVAID) infrastructure?",
    "answer": "navigation specification and navigation application.\u000b\u000baeronautical data defines waypoints, routes and procedures. Quality control processes are at every stage and a validation process is used to check the procedure is accurate.",
    "ref": "062.07.01.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8774084532633424",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1874",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State the difference between RNAV and RNP in terms of the requirement for on-board performance monitoring and alerting.",
    "answer": "RNP requires onboard performance monitoring and alerting. RNAV does not.",
    "ref": "062.07.02.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.472720495890826",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1876",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "List the basic functional requirements of the RNAV and RNP specifications?",
    "answer": "Continuous indication of lateral deviation, distance/bearing to active waypoint, \u000bGS or time to active waypoint, \u000bnavigation data storage and failure indication.",
    "ref": "062.07.02.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6293533407151699",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1878",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Interpret X in RNAV X or RNP X as?",
    "answer": "The lateral navigation (LNAV) accuracy (total system error) in nautical miles, which is expected to be achieved at least 95 per cent of the flight time by the population of aircraft operating within the given airspace, route or procedure.",
    "ref": "062.07.02.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8007399127818644",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1880",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNAV 10 and RNP 4 are used at what stage?",
    "answer": "in the oceanic/remote phase of flight.",
    "ref": "062.07.02.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0726546864025294",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1881",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNAV 5 is used iin what stage?",
    "answer": "In the en-route and arrival phases of flight.",
    "ref": "062.07.02.03.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5028064702637494",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1882",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNAV 2 and RNP 2 are also used as navigation specifications.",
    "answer": "RNP 2 - en route oceanic and en route continental\u000bRNAV 2 enroute continental, Arrival, Departure",
    "ref": "062.07.02.03.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.438232334330678",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1888",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNP 0.3 navigation specification is used when?",
    "answer": "in all phases of flight except for oceanic/remote and final approach, primarily for helicopters.",
    "ref": "062.07.02.03.11",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.8907919581979513",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1894",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Recognise the definition of radius to fix (RF) leg.Describe?",
    "answer": "Used when there is a requirement for a specific curved path in a terminal or approach procedure - it's a low level procedure. It's defined as a radius, an arc length and the fix at which is ends. \u000b\u000bSilly way to remember:\u000bRF - as in radio transmission - and you'd be making lots of RT calls in a terminal or approach procedure.",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.500183445867151",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1895",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Recognise the definition of a fixed radius transition (FRT).",
    "answer": "Used in en route procedures. Provides a more controlled (than a fly-by WP) transition from one route leg to another.\u000b\u000b\u000bSilly way to remember:\u000bFRT - a bit like Frite... chips... which you'd be having en route as part of your in-flight meal.",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1869373456574976",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1896",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: State the importance of respecting the flight director guidance and the speed constraints associated with an RF procedure.",
    "answer": "The FD will provide the correct ground path to follow.",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.3085542940534652",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1897",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain the difference between a fly-by-turn and a fly-over.",
    "answer": "As it sounds:\u000b\u000bFly over turn requires the WP to be overflown (circle around the WP) \u000b\u000bFly by (no circle, the turn can be initiated early to intercept the next leg.",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5690366318449378",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1898",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: State that the Aeronautical Radio, Incorporated (ARINC) 424 path terminators set the standards for?",
    "answer": "Coding the SIDs, STARs and instrument approach procedures (IAPs) from the official published government source documentation into the ARINC navigation database format.",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1825236636213958",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1899",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: State that the path terminators define a specific type of termination of the previous flight path.",
    "answer": "Not really sure of the full context implications of this. BGS says:\u000b\u000ba SID or STAR requires the route to be asseembled (coded) in a series of segments. Each segment usually consists of a type of flight path (great circle or direct track) and the thing that terminates is, eg, arriving at a fix. These are end-of-segment path terminators and they define a specific type of termination of the previous flight path.\u000b\u000bAlso just referred to as ARINC 424 path determinator. \u000b\u000bThis surely has to be the most pointless piece of knowledge in the whole syllabus....",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5964022376574576",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1900",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Define the term ‘offset flight path’.",
    "answer": "SLOP - strategic lateral offset procedure. in remote areas, deliberate offsets can be used as extra mitigation against collision. \u000b\u000bGPS is so accurate that aircraft are flying precisely the same routes. Tming erros could cause collisions (previous nav accuracy actually help prevent this risk).",
    "ref": "062.07.03.03.07",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2812307011336088",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1904",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Define ‘path definition error’ (PDE).",
    "answer": "The inability of the system to accurately specify the desired path.\u000b\u000b1 of 3 component errors - others: NSE and FTE",
    "ref": "062.07.04.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6731709530577064",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1905",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Define ‘flight technical error’ (FTE)?",
    "answer": "The FTE is the error in following the prescribed path, either by the auto-flight system or by the pilot.\u000b\u000b\u000b1 of 3 component errors - others: NSE and PDE",
    "ref": "062.07.04.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2113599516451358",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1906",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Define ‘navigation system error’ (NSE)?",
    "answer": "The inability of the system to determine actual position, perhaps because of a sensor failure, limits of accuracy of GNSS etc.\u000b\u000bThe accuracy of a navigation system may be referred to as NSE.\u000b\u000b\u000b1 of 3 component errors - others: FTE and PDE",
    "ref": "062.07.04.01.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4742564973421394",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1907",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: Define ‘total system error’ (TSE)?",
    "answer": "The geometric sum of the PDE, FTE and NSE equals the TSE.",
    "ref": "062.07.04.01.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0653545884415507",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1908",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "PBN: State that navigation accuracy depends on the TSE.",
    "answer": "The geometric sum of the PDE, FTE and NSE equals the TSE.",
    "ref": "062.07.04.01.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7571667367592454",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1910",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that on-board performance monitoring and alerting of flight technical errors is managed by?",
    "answer": "on-board systems or flight crew procedures.",
    "ref": "062.07.04.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6162676569074392",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1912",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that, dependent on the navigation sensor, the estimated position error (EPE) is compared with the required navigation specification. How is this displayed to the pilot?",
    "answer": "On the NAV Display as Actual or ANP - with an RNP standard and the EPE adjacent to it, eg:\u000b\u000bRNP 5 / EPE 1 (I think?)",
    "ref": "062.07.04.02.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4111331310123204",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1913",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain how a navigation system assesses the EPE.",
    "answer": "Through a 'kalman filter' computation, using inputs from multiple filters an taking into account their known errors. \u000b\u000bFrom wikipedia:\u000b\u000bFor statistics and control theory, Kalman filtering, also known as linear quadratic estimation (LQE), is an algorithm that uses a series of measurements observed over time, including statistical noise and other inaccuracies, and produces estimates of unknown variables that tend to be more accurate than those based on a single measurement alone, by estimating a joint probability distribution over the variables for each timeframe. The filter is named after Rudolf E. Kálmán, who was one of the primary developers of its theory.",
    "ref": "062.07.04.02.04",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1333214752376079",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1914",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Give an example of how the loss of the ability to operate in RNP airspace may be indicated by the navigation system.",
    "answer": "An alert is displayed prominently, usually on the Nav display. eg \u000b\u000b'UNABLE REQD NAV PERF-RNP'",
    "ref": "062.07.04.02.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0334867518395185",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1915",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that on-board performance monitoring and alerting of path definition error is managed by?",
    "answer": "Gross reasonableness checks of navigation data.",
    "ref": "062.07.04.02.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2062291214242577",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1917",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that abnormal and contingency procedures are to be used in case of loss of the PBN capability. Examples of these are?",
    "answer": "Radar monitoring by ATC, or changes of lfight level/routing or flying a conventional approach.",
    "ref": "062.07.04.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.543762605637312",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1922",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNAV 10 requires that aircraft operating in oceanic and remote areas be equipped with?",
    "answer": "At least two independent and serviceable long-range navigation systems (LRNSs) comprising an INS, an inertial reference system (IRS)/flight management system (FMS) or a GNSS.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.01.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2193657280877232",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1923",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that operators may extend their RNAV 10 navigation capability time by?",
    "answer": "updating \u000b\u000bI think this means updating the equipment using ground aids. Because an IRS/INU drifts, they have (apparently) 6.2 hours within RNAV 10 airspace.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.01.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.5332664181478322",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1925",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that manual data entry is acceptable for RNAV 5.",
    "answer": "Surprisingly little equipment - eg, 1 or more VOR/DME, DME/DME, INS, IRS, GNSS\u000b\u000bA nav database is not required meaning manual entry of data such as waypoints is permitted.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.02.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4284612461924553",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1927",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that pilots must not fly an RNAV 1, RNAV 2, RNP 1 or RNP 2 standard instrument departure (SID) or standard instrument arrival (STAR) unless it is?",
    "answer": "Retrievable by route name from the on-board navigation database and conforms to the charted route.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.03.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0845278650522232",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1928",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "RNP: State that the route may subsequently be modified - how?",
    "answer": "through the insertion (from the database) or deletion of specific waypoints in response to ATC clearances.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.03.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4854596983641386",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1929",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "RNP: State that the manual entry, or creation of new waypoints by manual entry, of either latitude and longitude or place/bearing/distance values is: not permitted? Or permitted?",
    "answer": "Not permitted",
    "ref": "062.07.05.03.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9054546654224396",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1932",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that pilots must not fly an RNP APCH unless?",
    "answer": "It is retrievable by procedure name from the on-board navigation database and conforms to the charted procedure.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.1724373796023428",
    "notes": "A system capability question",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1933",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an RNP APCH to LNAV minima is a: precision or non-precision?",
    "answer": "non-precision IAP designed for two-dimensional approach operations.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.02",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2068872079253196",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1934",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an RNP APCH to lateral navigation (LNAV)/vertical navigation (VNAV) minima has lateral guidance based on GNSS and vertical guidance based on?",
    "answer": "Either SBAS or barometric vertical navigation (Baro-VNAV).",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6096806614659728",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1936",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain why an RNP APCH to LNAV/VNAV minima based on Baro-VNAV may only be conducted when the aerodrome temperature is within a promulgated range if the barometric input is not automatically temperature-compensated.",
    "answer": "Lower temperatures cause uncompensated altimeters to over-read therefore aircraft are lower than indicated. \u000b\u000bAnd vice -versa - which could result in glidepath being too steep etc.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.05",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2435061242431402",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1937",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that the correct altimeter setting is critical for the safe conduct of an RNP APCH using Baro-VNAV.",
    "answer": "This seems obvious coming from the world of PARs and SRAs. However, of course, glidepath accuracy for ILS is independent of altimeter setting (notwithstanding decision height) etc",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.06",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4491094332188368",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1939",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that an RNP APCH to localiser performance with vertical guidance (LPV) minima is a three-dimensional operation.",
    "answer": "This would be using SBAS - pilots fly a geometric path in spaceto a DA\u000b\u000bThis is derived from the FAS data-block",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.08",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.9108368749730288",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1940",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNP APCH to LPV minima requires a final approach segment (FAS) data block.",
    "answer": "This is additional data in the nav database on the design of the approach to ensure repeatable, predictable path is flown.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.09",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0645649041980504",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1941",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNP approaches to LPV minima require SBAS.",
    "answer": "LPV - Localiser performance with vertical guidance.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.05.10",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.6227016979828477",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1944",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that RNP AR APCH requires authorisation.",
    "answer": "Another ambiguous vague term. This means operational approval - based on a/c performance, crew training, verification of database integrity.\u000b\u000bThese approaches take advantage of later system developments - egTF, RF legs etc",
    "ref": "062.07.05.06.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.4424925507046282",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1946",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that A-RNP incorporates the navigation specifications RNAV 5, RNAV 2, RNAV 1, RNP 2, RNP 1 and RNP APCH.",
    "answer": "It is expected that A-RNP will replace most if not all PBN specifications.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.07.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2719765864312649",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1948",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "State that a PinS departure is a departure procedure designed for?",
    "answer": "helicopters only.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.08.01",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.837283153552562",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "1950",
    "topic": "Radio Navigation",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Recognise the differences in the instructions ‘proceed VFR’ and ‘proceed visually’.",
    "answer": "Visually: \u000b\u000bMin visibility maybe below VFR limits but the FATO is a heliport and the area between the FATO and the IDF are protected. \u000b\u000b\u000bVFR\u000bFATO is not a heliport, area is not protected. Min visibility is that on the chart or as required for the class of airspace.",
    "ref": "062.07.05.08.03",
    "source": "EASA LOs",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.72871923353523",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "09/02/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2138",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "In terms of fuel planning/policy, what must an operator establish?",
    "answer": "A policy for purposes of flight planning and in-flight planning to ensure every fight carries sufficient fuel for the planned operation",
    "ref": "7.1",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0607870984822511",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2139",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "In an operators fuel policy, the quantity of fuel required for a flight will be the sum of: ?",
    "answer": "- Taxy fuel\u000b- Trip fuel\u000b- Reserve fuel (consisting of contingency, alternate, final reserve and additional fuel)\u000b- Extra Fuel",
    "ref": "7.1",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.7959227487444877",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2140",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain 'Taxy Fuel'?",
    "answer": "This quanity must not be less than that expected to be used prior to take-off. Local conditions at the departure aerodrome and APU must be taken into account. \u000b\u000bAn operator will usually have a standard allowance but the Aircraft Captain can vary this if appropriate.",
    "ref": "7.1",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.9749276540242136",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2141",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain 'Trip Fuel' and the flight stages that are considered when planning?",
    "answer": "This is the 'runway to runway' fuel. Must include:\u000b\u000bTake off and climb and departure routing\u000bFuel from top of climb to top of descent - ie, cruise\u000bTop of descent to approach including arrival procedure\u000bApproach and landing",
    "ref": "7.1",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3085546484217048",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2142",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain Reserve fuel (contingency) and the options available to operators for calculating it?",
    "answer": "Fuel for unforeseen events affecting the plan - eg, headwind, late departure, etc\u000b\u000bEither A: one of the following:\u000b- 5% of the trip fuel (or 5% remaining for in-flight)\u000b- 3% if alternate en route available\u000b- 20 mins flying time based on consumption and a consumption monitoring programme\u000b- An amount based on approved statistical analysis by the operator\u000b\u000bor B:\u000bAn amount for 5 mins at holding speed at 1500' above the destination in standard conditions.",
    "ref": "7.2",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.8773712548427283",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2143",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain Reserve fuel (Alternate Fuel) and the flight stages considered for calculating it?",
    "answer": "Alternate fuel must include:\u000b\u000bFuel for Missed approach to missed approach altitude including full MAP\u000b\u000bClime to cruise\u000b\u000bCruise\u000b\u000bDescent to approach\u000b\u000bApproach and landing",
    "ref": "7.2",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.5442398954182863",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2144",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain Reserve fuel (Final Reserve Fuel) and the flight stages considered for calculating it?",
    "answer": "(Note from CC - this looks similar to MLA)\u000b\u000bThe minimum quantity of fuel to be in the tanks when the aircraft lands. If a landing below final reserve looks likely then an emergency must be declared. \u000b\u000bFinal reserve fuel is:\u000b\u000bFor aeroplanes with reciprocating engines - fuel to fly for 45 mins\u000b\u000bTurbine engines: fuel to fly for 30mins at holding speed at 1500' above airfield elevation - in standard conditions, calculated based on planned mass at arrival.",
    "ref": "7.2",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3455745405517518",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "03/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fadec,fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2145",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain Reserve fuel (Additional Fuel) and its applicability?",
    "answer": "These cover 'what ifs' and don't always apply. eg, a de-pressurisation mid-atlantic would require a descent and cruise at lower altitude etc. \u000b\u000bAlso, if you do not nominate an alternate then Minimum ramp fuel must include additional fuel for 15 minutes holding at 1500' above the destination aerodrome.",
    "ref": "7.3",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.0310641964897513",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2146",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "Explain 'Extra Fuel' and its applicability?",
    "answer": "This is the Captain's discretion and might be added to allow for anticipated ATC delays or marginal weather etc.",
    "ref": "7.3",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.1875240043736994",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2147",
    "topic": "Flight Planning",
    "variant": "",
    "question": "What is 'Minimum Ramp Fuel' and list the constituent allowances?",
    "answer": "This is the amount of fuel that will be loaded into the aeroplane. It consists of:\u000b\u000bTaxy +\u000bTrip+\u000bContingency+\u000bAlternate+\u000bFinal Reserve\u000b\u000bAdditional Fuel maybe required\u000bExtra Fuel may also be loaded by the Captain if appropriate.",
    "ref": "7.3",
    "source": "BGS Flight Planning and Monitoring",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3805011999793351",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "04/05/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "fuel,if"
  },
  {
    "id": "2148",
    "topic": "Powerplant",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "If, during OEI, the NR drops below 95% what does the Tq limiting system allow?",
    "answer": "An increase in Tq from 128 to 133 at 1% tq per 1% decrease in Nr until 90% Nr. \u000b\u000bBelow 90% the power is constant at 133% and leaves a 3% margin from the max attainable Tq limitation (136%)of the gearbox (CC edit - I think this is actually a limit for the input shaft).",
    "ref": "06-98",
    "source": "Training Manual",
    "visibility": "Hidden",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2712681931443512",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "26/07/2022",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": ""
  },
  {
    "id": "2149",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "With reference to Tq, how much power should be used for take-off?",
    "answer": "Hover power plus 10% without exceeding TOP",
    "ref": "2.4.1",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "Knowledge",
    "weight": "0.3424316346645355",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2150",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "When operating to an elevated heli-port or with a bar-alt only what margin should be added to TDP?",
    "answer": "60'  - eg, 120' becomes 180'. This is to allow for baralt/static errors caused by rotor downwash etc.",
    "ref": "2.4.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.727095532696694",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2151",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "For a VTOL 1, describe the power settings to use and the rate of climb to aim for?",
    "answer": "Hover torque plus 10% with a ROC of 300'/min. At TDP adjust power to TOP (top of the yellow band)",
    "ref": "2.4.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7455601249821485",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2152",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "For a VTOL 1 take-off, describe the very initial manoeuvring from the ground prior to the rearwards climb?",
    "answer": "Lift to 4' hover, then rearwards 3m, then climb to 10' then initiate the rearwards climb.",
    "ref": "2.4.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.544230377767235",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2153",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "What would be the minimum acceptable TDP, as indicated on the BARALT, for a VTOL3 take-off without a serviceable RADALT?",
    "answer": "300'. \u000b\u000b60' must be added to baralt readings when radalt not available.",
    "ref": "2.4.4",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.0883490904234349",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2154",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Using an FCDS baralt, in the absence of a radalt, what is the height correction that is added to the LDP?",
    "answer": "180' is added (or 210' with standby baralt). eg, LDP for a VTOL1 becomes 300'",
    "ref": "2.7.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.2120396252721548",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2155",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "Define Take-Off Distance Required (for helicopters)?",
    "answer": "Horizontal distance required from the start of the take-off to the point at which Vtoss, a selected height and a positive climb gradient are achieved.",
    "ref": "4.1.2",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7647023950703442",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  },
  {
    "id": "2156",
    "topic": "Cat A",
    "variant": "P2+/T2+",
    "question": "For a VTOL 1 departure, what 3 conditions/considerations must be met with respect to obstacle?",
    "answer": "No significant obstacles present in the continued take-off area for the first 150m of the FATO\u000b\u000bNo significant obstacles present to the rear of the helicopter for at least 80m to climb rearwards to TDP\u000b\u000bWhen obstacles are present in the CTOA TDP height may be varied iaw procedures at Para 4.2.5",
    "ref": "4.2.4",
    "source": "OMB",
    "visibility": "Reveal",
    "type": "",
    "weight": "0.7394770244136452",
    "notes": "",
    "created": "12/12/2023",
    "modified": "04/06/2025",
    "verified": "",
    "status": "ok",
    "tags": "opc"
  }
]